本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 苏三 草之露 养兔子的格里森 易如反掌 尔后 黄豆芽 leleniuhappy 翻炒土豆
校对： 烟诺  Fringe   后期： 小滔
雅什・曹帕拉: 印度知名导演 （1932.9.27～2012.10.12）
本片为其遗作 谨向这位贡献了不少佳作的导演致敬
现代 列城市场 拉达克
喂 你干什么?
Hey, what are you doing?
长官 给阿南德少校送防爆衣
Bomb suit for Major Anand, sir
他不会穿的
He won't wear it
但是长官... 我觉得...
But sir... I mean...
你看着就是了
Keep watching
德万 情况怎么样?
What is it, Dewan?
长官 我搞不定
I can't figure it out, sir,
看起来这是通过无线遥控引爆的
it looks like a radio control servo with a switch,
但我找不到接收器
but I can't locate the receiver
X光也是什么都找不到
and the x-ray hasn't shown up anything either
你歇着吧 我来看看
You rest, I'll take a look
好的 长官
OK, sir
长官 他是不是就是那个传说中的
Sir, is this the same Major Samar Anand,
拆弹记录保持者 萨马・阿南德少校?
who has the record for the maximum number of bombs defused?
是的 他已拆了九十七枚炸弹
Yup, 97 bombs,
这是第九十八枚
this is the 98th,
而且 他拆弹的时候就是这样
and he goes into the lap of each bomb just like this,
不用任何防护
without any protection,
好像面对的不是炸弹
as if it's not a bomb,
而是他女朋友的臂弯
but the arms of his girlfriend
长官 所以人们都称他为"不死传奇"?
Sir, is that why they call him 'the man who cannot die'?
是的 "不死传奇"
Yes, 'The Man Who Cannot Die'
所有人都终将死去
All of us have to die one day
他也一样
and so will he,
但我从没在他眼睛里看到过对死亡的恐惧
until today I've never seen the fear of death in his eyes
我也不能理解他为什么选择这种生活
I can't understand the kind of fate he's had written for himself
他们把接收器藏在炸药里 然后用铅包住
They had hidden the receiver within the RDX and covered it with lead,
RDX：三次甲基三硝基胺 军用高能炸药
所以X光检查不出来
that's why the X-ray couldn't catch it
辛格 可以开放集市了
Singh, open up the market
是的 长官
Okay sir
阿玛努拉 长官 开放集市
Amaanullah, sir, open the market
你顽皮而狡黠的眼神
Your eyes, impish and mischievous
你傲慢而冷淡的笑容
Your laughter's nonchalant insolence
你随意披散的长发
Your hair unfurled their waves undone
我永或不忘
Never shall I forget
至死方休 至死方休
Until I breathe this life, Until I breathe this life
再握不到你的手
Your hand that abandoned mine
枉自凝视你渐远的背景
Your shadow that turned away it's gaze
再不得见你的面容
Your look that never looked back
我永或不忘
Never shall I forgive
至死方休 至死方休
Until I breathe this life, Until I breathe this life
你在雨中洒脱的舞姿
Your unabashed dancing in the rain
你傻傻的小任性
Your silly sulkings at all things small
你天真烂漫的小顽皮
Your innocent childlike mischief
足够我珍爱一生
Always I will love
不死不休 不死不休
Until I breathe this life, Until I breathe this life
你虚假的誓言和承诺
Your false vows and promises
你癫狂炽热的梦想
Your burning scorching dreams
你残忍无情的祷告
Your cruel ruthless prayers
我永远难以释怀
Always I will hate
不死不休 不死不休
Until I breathe this life, Until I breathe this life
爱无止境
上帝保佑...
In the name of God...
操!
Oh shit!
这水太凉了...
the water is freezing...
救命啊!
Help!
兵哥!
Soldier!
水好冷... 冷死了... 求求你...
water... col... cold... freezing... please
求你... 救救我...
help please...
求你了...
please...
如果我死了怎么办?
what if I had died?
你就不能早点来救我吗?
Couldn't you have come earlier?
你是个军人...
You're a soldier...
你... 你们不是宣过誓...
you'll... have taken some oath haven't you...
要保卫同胞的生命吗?
to save lives of fellow lndians?
刚刚我的情况多么危急...
I was in such a dangerous situation...
我可能会死掉...
I could have died...
混蛋!
Arsehole!
漂亮!
Nice!
哦 天啊!
Oh God!
亚基拉!
Akira!
你居然真的去做了!
I can't believe you actually did it!
伙计们 掏钱!
Just pay up guys!
你快把我搞破产了
I'm going bankrupt because of you,
这是三周以来的第五次大冒险了
this is the fifth dare in 3 weeks,
拜托你能少去几次吗?
for once can you not complete a dare?
山姆 别像个胆小鬼
Stop being such a wuss, Sam,
再过两天你们就要去伦敦探索频道工作了
two more days and you all will be in the London discovery office
而我却只能呆在德里
and I will be stuck in Delhi,
那时你们就会思念我了
and then you will miss me and you'll be like
你们会想当初把所有的钱都给亚基拉就好了
I wish I had given Akira all my money,
毕竟她这个实习生也该劳有所得
after all she got paid shit as an intern
我才不会想你
I won't miss you
听好了 停下手头上的活儿
Alright, you lot listen up, stop whatever it is you are doing,
今天我休息
it's my day off,
今天我不想看到你们这群蠢货
so I don't want to see any of your ugly faces today,
但是明天早上我要你们
but tomorrow morning I want your boney arses,
七点准时回到这儿
back here at 7 o'clock sharp
好的 队长
Aye, aye, Captain
凯瑟琳!
Catherine!
滚开 亚基拉
Piss off, Akira
你有考虑过把带我去伦敦吗?
Did you think about taking me with you to London?
是的 我考虑过 答案是不行 所以滚吧
Yes, I did and the answer is no, so get out of my face
贱人!
Bitch!
哦 天啊...
Oh, God, man...
阿琼 我说了我们没戏了
Arjun, I told you it's over between us man,
别再打过来了...
stop calling me...
阿琼
Arjun,
我们才处了六个月 你怎么就放不下呢?
it's only a 6-month relationship, why are you getting so hyper?
简单点说 你还爱我 但我已经不爱你了
You still love me but now I don't, simple,
拜托 放手吧 以后再说!
come on, get over it, we'll talk later!
萨马・阿南德...
Samar Anand...
我不知道自己是怎么活过这二十五年的
In a way, I had already lived twenty-five years,
但我的人生从这一天起 才真正开始
but my life, actually began on this day,
我人生的第一天
The first day of my story,
我第一次看见雪花飞舞
the first time I saw snow fall,
第一次目睹天使在漫天雪花里穿行
the first time I saw an angel glide across the snow
非得现在下雪吗?
Did You have to make the snow fall right now,
就不能再等十分钟?
couldn't You have waited 10 minutes more?
害得我这么贵重的裙子都被风雪打湿了
Such an expensive dress, it got wet
总之 我的成绩出来了
Anyway, my results are out,
全校第一诶
I topped the university
爸爸他很高兴
Dad is very happy
谢谢您
Thank You,
我遵守诺言我今后再也不吃巧克力了...
and yes, like I promised You, no more chocolates from today...
绝不 我保证
never, I promise
现在请听好了 今天的事情很重要
Okay, now listen carefully, today our work is very important
比娜婶婶家要办一场音乐会
There's a music ceremony at Bina aunty's
桑格夫人想把我介绍给她儿子
and Mrs.Sanger wants to hook me up
就那个华尔街银行家
with her wall street banker son
请求您 千万千万确保他不喜欢我
Please, please, please make sure that he doesn't fancy me,
我也会尽量惹他厌恶
I will also fully try to make sure but,
但您知道的 印度男人追我的时候都太蠢了
You know how Indian boys behave stupid, when they're around me
无论如何 我也不会嫁给印度人的
and in any case, I am not going to marry an Indian boy,
还记得我跟你说的话吗?
remember me telling You this?
请不要让我嫁给印度男孩
Please don't get me married to any Indian boy,
他们肤色都那么暗沉
they are all very brown
请帮我找一个帅气的白人男孩吧
Please find me a nice handsome white boy,
求你了 求你了
please, please, please
但是您也要确保爸爸不喜欢那个银行家
But You have to make sure that Dad doesn't like that banker,
主啊... 我可决不会和爸爸作对的
because You know... I can never fight with Dad
所以求您了
So please, please, please
千万不要让这种情况发生 我保证...
don't let this happen and I promise that...
我保证今后再也不穿皮草大衣了
I promise, I will stop wearing fur coats from today,
您知道我有多爱皮草的
and You know how much I love fur
可以吗?
Okay?
一言为定?
Deal?
请您费心啦
Please take care of this
谢谢
Thanks
哦 耶稣大人 真够你忙的
Wow, sir Jesus, what specimens You have to bear,
真是份苦差事
very hard work, sir,
上帝保佑您吧 先生
God bless You, sir
喂 萨马 你磨叽什么呢?
Hey Samar, what you doing man?
中午你就该扫完的
You were supposed to be finished by lunch time
杰克先生 不要着急嘛
No worry, Jack Sir,
再给二十分钟 我会扫的干干净净
I finish twenty minutes fully clean, shaving and shining
我半个小时后来接你 务必要扫完
I'm picking you up in half an hour, make sure it's done
好的 一定 回见
Done, done, okay, ta-ta, see you, bye bye,
这个国家会从地上长出雪来
from the ground in this country grows snow,
长出雪白雪白的雪来呦
grows white white snow
扎因 天亮了 起床了
Come on Zain, it's morning, get up
伦敦正张开她的双臂呼唤你呢
London's opened her arms and is calling you
快起来 快 快 快
Come on, get up, hurry up, hurry up, hurry up
拜托
Oh man
伦敦一点不待见我 朋友
London is upset with me, my friend,
我连半份工都打不到
it does not give me even a half day of work
说她张开双臂欢迎我简直是放屁
It's rubbish that she has her arms open for me
伦敦 帮帮我吧
Oh London, do something for me,
看来我可能要回拉合尔了
it seems I might have to return to Lahore
对了 卡普尔大叔催缴房租了
Oh man, Kapoor uncle, was asking for the rent,
他说我们今天就得搬出去
he was saying we have to vacate the flat today
安心吃你的鸡蛋吧
You relax and eat your eggs,
我来解决
I'll handle Uncle
确定?
Sure?
对 当然
Yes, for sure
你真好
You're too good
- 上帝保佑你 - 再见
- God bless - Bye,
回头见
we'll meet again
这小子... 又留下了一个星期的房租
Rascal... has again left money for the whole week,
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 亦曾欣喜 亦曾悲伤 #
Wanders with a smile...
# 他只身流浪 #
...and a tear
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 处处为家 #
Belonging to all
# 又处处无家 #
Yet none to call my own
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 身披彩虹的斑斓 #
Dipped in rainbow colours,
# 歌声如夜莺般婉转 #
with voice of a nightingale
# 步伐如日光般激昂 #
With steps radiating sunlight,
# 时而有流影投射在肩头 #
with palanquin of cooling shade
# 身披彩虹的斑斓 #
Dipped in rainbow colours,
# 歌声如夜莺般婉转 #
with voice of a nightingale
# 步伐如日光般激昂 #
With steps radiating sunlight,
# 时而有流影投射在肩头 #
with palanquin of cooling shade
# 找寻被乌云遮蔽的明月 #
Seeking the moon amidst dark clouds
# 倾听沉默风声的低吟 #
Listening for the mute wind's song
# 我的朋友无处不在 #
This friend of mine is everywhere
# 即便不得相见 仍有芬芳沁鼻 #
Unseen to the eye, fragrant to the smell
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 心中的挚爱 没有相聚 何来别离 #
With the beloved, no union, nor separation
# 爱的囚徒 逃不脱的羁绊 #
Prisoner of love, never unchained
# 你答应我会在梦中相见 #
Your promise of appearing in a dream
# 我竟不敢睡去 #
Keeps sleep far from my eyes
# 我呼吸的节奏越来越快 #
The breath I take quickens
# 我脉搏的律动且行且缓 #
My pulse becomes fainter still
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 亦曾欣喜 亦曾悲伤 #
Wanders with a smile...
# 他只身流浪 #
...and a tear
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 处处为家 #
Belonging to all
# 又处处无家 #
Yet none to call my own
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
给您 一公斤斑节对虾
Here you go, 1 kilo tiger prawn,
七条鲈鱼 六只鱿鱼还有一只章鱼
7 sea bass, 6 squids and 1 octupussy
萨马 干得好
Excellent, Samar
哦 还有个东西...
And oh, something waiting...
好东西 瞧...
special, see...
萨马 你帮我弄到了鹅肝酱?
Ah, Samar, you got my foie gras?
你的鹅肝? 你不是问过嘛 我就去找来了
Your fodegrass? You ask, I get
谢谢你 萨马 你总是那么照顾我
Thank you, Samar, you always come through for me
听着 如果你不愿意干这行了
Look, if you ever get tired of this,
你可以来我的餐厅工作
I have a job waiting for you in one of my restaurants,
谢谢您 先生
Thank you, sir,
好诶
Fodegrass
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentleman,
请恭祝这对新订婚的情侣
the newly engaged couple
罗杰和我美丽的女儿米拉
Roger and my beautiful daughter Meera
喂 你不是唱沙耶歌的那个人吗?
Hey, aren't you that guy who sings that Challa song?
对 如假包换 女士
Yes, same to same, ma'am
你在这里干什么?
What are you doing here?
女士 在伦敦挣钱太难了
Madam, in your London it is very difficult to earn pounds,
一份工作可糊不了口 所以我打了两份工
it is not possible to buy food with one job, so double shift
耶稣大人没有成全你呀?
So, sir Jesus did not listen to you?
什么?
What?
那天在教堂 你对耶稣大人说
That day in the church, you told sir Jesus,
让那个男人不要喜欢你
to make that boy not like you,
但是今天你定婚了...
but today it is your arrangement...
是订婚
Engagement
是的 是的 也差不多
Yes, yes, same
你怎么知道这些的?
How do you know all this?
那天我在教堂外扫雪
That day outside the church, I'm cleaning snow
听别人的祷告可不是件好事
Listening to others' confessions is not a good thing,
而且你那天听到的话不是在说这个男人
and for your information on that day it did not work out with that boy,
耶稣先生还是一如既往地成全了我
so sir Jesus did listen to me like always
我认识罗杰很多年了
I have known Roger for many years,
他人很不错
he's a really nice guy,
我也很开心
and I am very happy
看起来不像
It does not look like it
你他妈...?
What the f...?
今天是我这一生中的大日子
It's the biggest day of my life today,
我非常开心
and I am very, very happy,
明白吗?
got it?
不明白
Not got,
因为当那个所谓的好男人给你戴上戒指时
because when that nice guy, was making you wear the ring,
你没有望着他的眼睛
you were not looking into his eyes,
而是看着别人...
you were looking at everyone else...
现在 你离开了自己的订婚典礼
and now, you've left your own engagement celebration,
独自坐在这里 又是为什么?
and are sitting here alone, why?...
你又为什么要向一个陌生人解释你的决定?
and why are you trying to explain your decision to a stranger?
说... 明白了吧
Go... got it
快来米拉 叔叔找你都快找疯了
Come on Meera uncle's going nuts looking for you
威尔... 我找到她了
Will... I found her
去他妈的...
What the f...
新的商标能同时传达出办店的理念和形象
The new logo will reflect the ideals and images of both chains,
总计二十五家连锁超市
a total of 25 new supermarkets
将分别进驻到六个新城镇
will be opened in six new towns
整个兼并和扩张的过程将会耗时六个月
and the whole merger and expansion will take six months
谢谢
Thank you
罗杰 干得好 你考虑的很周到
Well done. Roger, you've thought about everything
我想我可以考虑退休了
I think it's time for me to think about my retirement,
我马上就五十岁了 是时候该退休了
I am turning 50, best time to retire,
您五十岁生日是什么时候?
When is your Golden Jubilee?
米拉 我们应该办个盛大的生日宴会
Meera, we should plan a big party
别担心 我已经为生日宴会筹划了一年多了
Don't worry, I've been planning this party for more than a year now,
这是给最特别的父亲筹划的特别庆祝
it's going to be the most special party for the most special father
是的 然后就是我女儿的婚礼了
Yes, and after that my daughter will get married and then,
我这个非常特别的父亲 就要变成孤家寡人啦
from a very special father I'll turn into a very lonely father
我不会丢下你不管的
But that will only happen if I leave you alone,
我结婚后 罗杰会来和我们住在一起
after our marriage Roger will stay with us
我什么时候这么说过?
When did this happen?
就是现在 这是我新增的小条款
Just now, just a small little clause I've added in the contract
并且不容商议
and it's non negotiable
罗杰 抱歉啊 她随我呀
Sorry Roger, she's gone on me,
是个非常固执的商业女性
a very stubborn business woman,
学着适应吧
you will have to deal with it
我尽量 尽量吧
I am trying, I am trying
给 五百镑
Here, 500 pounds,
算你一个月的报酬 每天一小时
for an hour of your time every day, for one month
你想买凶杀谁?
Who do I have to kill?
你教我唱歌
You'll have to teach me how to sing
你为什么要和我学唱歌?
Why do you want to learn how to sing from me?
我爸爸来自费朗达尔
My Dad's from Jalandhar,
他希望我能讲旁遮普语
and he's always wished that I could speak Punjabi,
但是我没有机会学
but I was never able to learn it
下个月就是他五十岁的生日了
It's his 50th birthday next month
我想唱首旁遮普歌 给他个惊喜
and I want to surprise him by singing a Punjabi song,
就像你之前唱的那样
Iike the kind that you sing,
你愿意教我唱歌吗?
so will you teach me?
五百英镑能让我的生活发生翻天覆地的变化
That way 500 pounds will turn my life around,
但如果我收了这笔钱
but if I take these
我自己也会发生翻天覆地的变化
then I may also completely turn around
我给你解释下
I'll explain
我妈妈从小就教导我
My mother has taught me,
教别人是不能收钱的
never take money for teaching someone,
所以现在你知道我的... 额 难处了吧?
so now you understanding my, uh, problem?
既然如此 那你就免费教我好啦
So in that case teach me without taking money
小姐 别看我长得傻乎乎的
Madam, I only look like,
但我其实一点也不傻
but I am not that big a fool, not dumbo
那算了吧
Fine
唉 等下等下 我们做个交易如何?
Okay, one minute, one second, can we do a deal?
我教你唱动听的旁遮普语歌曲
I teach you beautiful Punjabi song
但作为回报 你要教我说标准的英式英语
and return gift you teach me good gentleman's English
小姐 这可是个超级划算的交易啊
this is now fair and handsome deal ma'am,
一个月后你就能在你爸爸的生日派对上
in one month you singing like the Nightingale Lata Mangeshkar,
用像夜莺一样美妙声音为他献唱
for your father's birthday
而我能用一口流利标准的英语和白人们聊田
and I speak fit-fat constipation with the white in full tip-top English
那叫聊天
Conversation
都一样的嘛
Same to same
一言为定咯
Done, done, London let's do it
一言为定
Done, done, London
不好意思
Uh sorry
请您保佑我能说一口流利的旁遮普语
Please make sure my Punjabi rocks,
我希望那天成为我爸爸生命中最快乐的一天
I wish that day to be Dad's happiest day
请保佑我 我向您保证...
Please help me and I promise...
我保证再也不抽烟了... 绝对不抽了
I promise... I will never smoke again... ever
早... 早上好
good... good morning
女士 这是您点的牛排
Steak for the lady
先生 这是您点的鲑鱼
and Salmon for the gentleman,
请慢用
enjoy
米拉
Meera
米拉 别生气啊 我开玩笑的
Meera listen, I was joking...
等下 先生 您还没结账
Excuse me sir you haven't paid
米拉 我身上没钱啊
Meera I don't have money
我们村用旁遮普语说叫Sirsa
Sirsa is the name of my village, in Punjab
我爸爸和祖辈的人都参了军
My father and forefathers all served in the army,
但他们全部都战死沙场
but in some war or other they gave their lives fighting
所以到我这一代 我妈妈就不让我参军了
When it was my time my mother refused to let me join,
她省吃俭用攒够了钱 把我送到这里
she somehow saved up money and sent me here
她坚信我会在这里闯出一片天地
She had this unsaid faith in me and felt that I'd do well here
她说我很会讨人喜欢
She says that I can win people's love
这种人是一定会成功的
and those who can win love will never lose
这就是女性的知觉
Solid maternal instant
是直觉
Instinct
我读的就是知觉
Instant
好吧 随便吧...
Okay, what eves...
一个一个来 慢用
Come, please come, bon appetite
来 下一个
Come, come in,
慢用
Bon appetite...
你每周五都来这里?
Do you come here every Friday?
是啊
Yes!
只有这里?
Just here?
不啊 我每周一会去孟加拉孤儿收养所
No, there's a Bangladeshi orphanage that I go to on Mondays
还有吗?
And...
每周三我去一个妇女救济站
On Wednesdays I go to a women's shelter
还有没?
And...
每周日去老年之家帮忙
A senior citizens' home on Sundays
还有吗?
And...
就这些
That's it
就这点儿?
That's it...
周二 周四和周六的时间
Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays,
都浪费了啊 太可惜了
they're all wasted, very bad
特蕾莎修女终其一生行善
Mother Teresa gave up her whole life,
你好啊 我正在给她讲道理呢
oye, explain something to this girl
你好啊 小胖墩
Oye, fatty,
你要吃多少啊 该开始节食了
how much will you eat, start a diet,
大家都过来吧 每人可以领份免费的食物
come all, free food for everyone
一分耕耘一分收获
How much you give is how much you get,
这是生活教会我的
I've learnt this in life,
但是如果每个人都只是一味的索取而不思回报
but if everybody keeps asking for more and no one gives back,
那谁还愿意分享?
then how will anything be shared?
很多时候 鱼与熊掌是不能兼得的
To get something you have to lose something
这就是你总喜欢和耶稣大人做交易的原因吧?
So that's why you keep making deals with sir Jesus
不是做交易... 而是虔诚地向上帝祈祷
Not deals... prayers that I make earnestly,
这也就是为什么上帝会应允我所有的愿望
and that's why your sir Jesus has agreed to everything I've told him
是嘛 那你让他教你唱歌好了
Okay, so tell Him to teach you how to sing
不用操心 我已经向他祈祷过了
Don't worry, I've already spoken to Him
真的啊...
Really...
上帝也会说旁遮普语?
Sir Jesus knows Punjabi too?
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
太不公平了
This is so not fair,
在我的帮助下 你的英语提高了那么多
I've managed to improve your English so much
但你连一首歌都还没教会我
and you're not able to teach me even one song
你已经学会唱歌了
You've already learnt how to sing,
而且你的旁遮普语也讲得很流利
you're also speaking perfect Punjabi,
语调也没什么大问题
the tune is also fine
那问题出在哪里啊?
What's the problem then?
问题在于你没有把情感注入到你的歌声中去
The problem is that there is no joy when you sing,
你的歌声里充满了恐惧
only fear,
你害怕吵到旁边的那位白人女士
you're scared this white woman will be disturbed
你怕吓到那些踢足球的人
Scared that these guys playing football,
怕他们会把你误认为是
will think
从某个印度山沟沟里逃出来的
you've runaway from some poor lndian village
振作起来
Come on,
如果当着这么点人的面你都不敢唱
if you can't sing in front of two or three strangers,
那到时候在几百号人面前你怎么敢开口?
how will you sing to a hundred people at the party?
混开!
Oh f... off!
你总是这样
Now this you enjoyed doing
米拉・塔帕尔小姐 虽然你总是装的一本正经
Miss Meera Thapar, the girl you are when you act dignified,
但你肯本不是那样的人
you're not,
你就是那种偷偷溜出来抽烟
you're that girl who sneaks out to smoke a cigarette,
总是出口成脏的女人
and keeps cussing this what the f...? What the f...? word.
我才不是那样的人
I am not that girl
电话借我用下
I need your phone please,
抱歉
excuse me,
稍等片刻
one second
玛利亚你好 我是萨马
Hello Maria, Samar this side,
麻烦你今晚带我的一个朋友一起去隧道那边
yes I want you to bring a friend of mine to the tunnel tonight ok,
她晚点会联系你的... 玛利亚 还有一点
she will call you... and Maria...
她这个人比较害羞 所以你帮她打扮下吧
she is a little shy type so make her like you,
弄的性感点 漂亮点 好 晚上见
Iittle sexy, un dos tres, ok bye
玛利亚和我一样在餐馆工作
Maria works in the restaurant with me
每周日晚我们所有人都会小聚一下
and every Sunday night all of us party together
你现在有她的号码了 六点之后联系她
You have the number in your phone, call her after six
那里没人认识你...
And no one knows you there...
所以这一晚 放下包袱 随心而动吧
so for just one night listen to your heart
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
因为我想让你知道你自己到底是个什么样的人
Because I want to show you who you really are
来吧 亲爱的
Come on, babe
嗨 玛利亚
Hey, Maria!
你好啊
hi
最近还好吧?
What's up?
我去去就来
I'll will be right back
壮汉 去把她拿下！
Go get her tiger!
嗨 玛利亚
Hey Maria!
嗨
Hi...
我马上就回来
I'll be right back
你好...
Hello...
我叫拉兹
I'm Raj,
你叫?
you are?
我叫蒂娜...
Tina...
意大利人吗?
Italian?
印度人
Indian
你看起来一点也不像印度人啊
You don't look Indian at all
一看你就是印度人
And you look completely Indian
何以见得?
Why?
你不喜欢印度男人?
You don't like lndian men?
印度男人好无趣的
They're very boring,
我喜欢有点冒险精神的男人
I like a bit of danger in a man
那你来这里岂不是如鱼得水嘛
So then this place is like a buffet for you,
你看 这么多人任你挑啊
and in any case since you've come they're all just waiting for your cue
随便挑一个吧
Take your pick
没看见中意的
I don't see anybody here,
没看见那种能伴我同行的人
somebody who'd walk side by side with me,
那种只需一个眼神就能掳获我芳心的人
who'd look into my eyes and steal my heart
那就只能祝你好运喽 印度姑娘
Best of luck, Indian girl
拉兹...
Raj...
才说几句你就放弃了啊
You give up too easily
我又没想讨你欢心
I wasn't even trying
为什么? 难道你不喜欢我?
Why, you don't like me?
我对你有好感
I like you,
但我知道你现在想寻求点新鲜事物
but at the moment you're looking for something else
当你倦了累了 自然会回到这里
When you get tired you'll come back here
万一我不回来了呢?
And if I don't?
你会回来的
You'll come
因为那个能伴你同行的人
...because for someone who'd walk by your side,
那个会深情的望着你的人
for someone who'd look into your eyes,
那个能够掳获你芳心的人就在这里
for someone who'd steal your heart,
除此之外别无他人
there's no one else here
米拉 赶紧的 你可不能错过这个啊
Come on Meera, you've got to see this
# 爱情就是全部 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is all. Love is sweet
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 爱情就是全部 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is all. Love is sweet
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 来吧 深情注视着我的眼睛 #
Come, look me in the eye
# 我的心火已被点燃 #
My heart is on fire
# 来吧 再靠近一点 #
Come, just a little closer
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 爱情就是全部 #
Love is all
# 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is sweet
# 爱情就是全部 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is all. Love is sweet
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 热恋让我们欣喜若狂 #
Burning with love is bliss
# 让我们的呼吸交融在一起 #
Let your breath mingle with mine
# 今晚是属于我们的爱的夜晚 #
Tonight is our night of love
# 明天爱情将去向何方 #
Tomorrow it belongs to another
# 让我们翻转皎洁的明月 #
Let's toss the moon like a coin
# 看她将作何选择
See what lands,
你美丽的脸庞 还是我美好的生活 #
your face or my life
# 爱情就是全部 #
Love is all
# 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is sweet
# 爱情就是全部 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is all. Love is sweet
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 来吧 深情注视着我的眼睛 #
Come, look me in the eye
# 我的心火已被点燃 #
My heart is on fire
# 来吧 再靠近一点 #
Come, just a little closer
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 爱情就是全部 #
Love is all
# 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is sweet
# 爱情就像一条奔腾不止的河流 #
Love is an unstoppable river
# 随着奔涌的波浪一路向前 #
Float on its waves and see
# 轻轻的踏上一朵云彩 #
Step lightly on a cloud
# 双足漂浮在空中 #
Your feet will find no ground
# 心无止境 #
The heart is without borders
# 无可阻挡 #
No lines can divide it
# 爱情就是全部 #
Love is all
# 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is sweet
# 爱情就是全部 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is all. Love is sweet
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 来吧 深情注视着我的眼睛 #
Come, look me in the eye
# 我的心火已被点燃 #
My heart is on fire
# 来吧 再靠近一点 #
Come, just a little closer
# 欢迎来到爱的世界 #
Welcome to the world of love
# 爱情就是全部 #
Love is all
# 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is sweet
# 爱情就是全部 #
Love is all
# 爱情甜美无比 #
Love is sweet
今晚是我这辈子最开心的一晚 萨马
I've had the best time of my life, Samar,
太感谢你了
thank you so much,
我真不知道该怎么感谢你好!
thank you, thank you, thank you
你现在知道自己其实是个坏女孩了吧
You know you're actually this bad ass girl,
实在搞不懂你怎么会生在那样正统的家庭
how you were born into such a fancy family, I can't understand
既然我这么坏 那就别和我做朋友喽
If I'm that bad, don't be friends with me
谁说我要和你做朋友啦?
Who wants to be friends?
不过既然我已经爱上了你
Now that I have fallen for you,
我有什么办法呢?
what do I do about that?
不是开玩笑 我是真的已经...
I'm not joking, I have really fallen in...
... 爱上你了
...Iove
你如此不羁的一面
It's this bad ass behaviour of yours,
完全隐藏在你正经的外表下
hiding behind this well behaved suave person,
恰恰是这点让我如醉如痴
that's trapped me
萨马...
Samar...
是的 我知道你要说什么...
Yes, I know...
你就要嫁给那个英国男人了
you're getting married to that English guy,
而且我们之间的约定也已经完成了
and now our contract is also over
所以也没有理由再见面了
so there's no reason to meet
你不用紧张
So no tension,
你的车来了 我们就此分道扬镳
your train's come, you go your way and I go mine,
一切到此为止
the end
本车的终点站是斯坦莫尔
This train terminates at Stanmore
米拉...
Meera...
如果我现在吻你...
If I kiss you...
你会煽我一巴掌吗?
will you slap me?
我赌你不会煽我
I don't think you will slap me
你没煽我
You didn't slap me,
你没煽我呦
you didn't slap me
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
# 让他把我带走 #
...and abduct me
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
# 我中有他 他中有我 #
I am just like him. He's just like me
# 他的笑声好似清晨的第一缕阳光 #
His laughter is like the morning sunlight
# 当他闭上双眼 便是无尽的黑暗 #
Soothing darkness falls when he closes his eyes
# 我中有他 他中有我 #
I am just like him. He's just like me
# 他的笑声好似清晨的第一缕阳光 #
His laughter is like the morning sunlight
# 当他闭上双眼 那便是无尽的黑暗 #
Soothing darkness falls when he closes his eyes
# 我中有他 他中有我 #
I am just like him. He's just like me
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
# 让他把我带走 #
...and abduct me
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
晚上好啊 米拉
Good evening, Meera
我真饿死了
I'm famished
你想吃点东西吗?
You want to eat?
炒面来喽
Chum va fa
米拉・塔帕尔小姐
So, Miss Meera Thapar,
你今天来是因为你也爱上我了吗?
so you've also fallen in love
两天没见着我就受不了 是不是?
You couldn't live without me for more than two days, right?
要不我们再来一个约定?
Let's do the done done London deal
我就要... 嫁给罗杰了
I am going to get married... to Roger,
这是我爸爸的意思
because that's what my father wants
从小爸爸就尽力满足我所有的愿望
He's always given me everything I've ever wanted
这是第一次我有机会能满足他的愿望
This is the first time he's asked something of me,
我不能拒绝他
I can't say no to him
我妈妈很早就抛下我和爸爸 跟别的男人跑了
My mother left my father and ran away with someone else,
那时我只有十二岁
I was twelve then
这些年来都是爸爸一个人照顾我
My father has taken care of me by himself
他总能设法满足我所有的愿望
He has always fulfilled my wishes,
现在我就只有他一个亲人了
we're the only family we have,
我们俩相依为命...
there's no one else...
我从没跟别人说过这些 就连罗杰也不知道
I haven't told this to anyone before now, not even Roger
我之所以跟你说这些 是因为你必须要帮我
I'm telling you this because you have to help me
我们俩必须一起对上帝发誓
Both of us, have to make a promise in front of Him,
我们仅仅只是朋友关系
that we'll remain just friends
绝不越界
and will never cross this line
如果我们当中的任何一个食言
and if we break this promise,
上帝可以以任何方式惩罚我们
He can punish us in any way He chooses
米拉 我不愿和你只是做朋友
I can't be friends with you, Meera,
不过你不用担心 我是不会越界的
but don't worry I will never cross any line,
我不用向上帝发誓就可以做到
and for that I don't need to make any kind of promise to God
这个誓言不是用来约束你的行为
This isn't for you, Samar,
而是用来约束我自己的
this is for me,
只有这样我才不会犯错
so that I don't make any mistake,
只有这样我才不会心软
so that I may not grow weak,
只有这样我才能够不越界
so that I may not cross the line
萨马 拜托了
Please Samar,
帮我这一次吧
for me
# 你走在我身边 却并不靠近我 #
Walk by my side leaving a space between us
# 你近在咫尺 却宛若千里 #
Put your heart or hand there
# 我走在你被拉长的影子里 #
I walk in the shade cast by your shadow
# 你走在我身边 却并不靠近我 #
Walk by my side leaving a space between us
# 你近在咫尺 却宛若千里 #
Put your heart or hand there
# 我走在你被拉长的影子里 #
I walk in the shade cast by your shadow
# 我中有他 他中有我 #
I am just like him. He's just like me
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
# 让他把我带走 #
...and abduct me
# 哦 朋友们 请不要叫我希尔 #
O friends, do not call me Heer
# 请叫我塞班 #
I am Sahiban now
# 让我的白马王子策马而来吧 #
Let any Mirza come on a horse...
- 早上好 小姐 - 早上好
- Good morning ma'am - Good morning
你有个包裹
Here is a parcel for you
我亲爱的米拉
My dearest Meera,
我在杂志上读到了你结婚的消息
I read about your marriage in a magazine
情不自禁给你寄了点东西
and couldn't help myself
这么多年过去了
It's been so many years and not one day has gone by,
没有一天我不想着你
when I haven't thought of you,
但是我向你父亲保证过 我永远都不会联系你
but I promised your father that I would never contact you
你每年过生日的时候
For all your birthdays
我都会买一份礼物
I'd buy a gift,
给你写一封信
and write a long letter addressed to you
然后把它们保存到柜子里
and then put them both away in the cupboard,
但是这次我再也控制不住自己了
but this time I couldn't stop myself
每个母亲都有这样的梦想
Every mother has a dream
梦想着亲手给女儿穿上她的结婚莎丽
to dress her daughter in her wedding sari herself,
莎丽：印度妇女用以裹身包头的整段布
但是我知道...
but I know that...
很多年前我就失去了这项权利
I lost this right many years ago
这件莎丽 就是我当年
The wedding sari that I wore
穿着来到你父亲家的那件
and came to your father's house,
我为了这一天一直仔细保存着
I've kept very carefully for this day
如果你觉得可以 请穿上它
If you think it is okay, wear it,
我会觉得好像我也亲临了你的婚礼
I will feel like I am also a part of your wedding
我知道你恨我
I know that you hate me,
但是我每天都向上帝祈祷
but I pray to God everyday,
希望有一天你能原谅我
hoping that one day you'll forgive me
愿你被无尽的爱包围着
Lots and lots of love
享有无尽的快乐
and lots of happiness,
你的母亲 波亚
your mother, Pooja
旁遮普 如果用英语发音的话
Punjab, as English say,
鲍伯・迪伦就是从那儿来的
Bob Dylan was from there,
鲍柏・辛格・迪伦 鲍勃变成勃勃
Babbar Singh Dhillon, Bob became Bub
那么现在你想怎么办?
So now what do you want to do?
我不知道
I don't know
米拉不知道
Meera doesn't know,
但是蒂娜知道怎么做
but Tina knows what to do
出发?
Should we go?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
跟你在做一样的事情呀
The same thing you're doing
你今天是不是有点太放松了?
Aren't you taking it a little too easy today?
前些天你那么忙
These days you are so busy
我都没机会跟你呆在一起
I don't get a chance to spend time with you
即使你离我这么近 却还是感觉很遥远
Even with you so close to me you're still not with me,
等待着你的时间里 我度日如年
awaiting your return I can't see the end of the day
别做这种无聊的诗了 伊姆兰
Stop this boring poetry of yours, lmran
- 挺烦人的 - 好吧
- It's annoying.- Okay
嘿 P小姐! P小姐!
Hey Miss P! Miss P!
什么着急事儿呀 亨利?
Where is the fire, Henry?
有人在门廊那儿等你 P小姐
Someone's waiting for you at the porch, Miss P
等我?
For me?
我今天没有约啊
I've no appointments today
是餐馆来的人
It's those people from the restaurant
我告诉他们来取葡萄酒的样品
I told them to come and sample the wines
那么他们找我干什么?
So why are they asking for me?
因为他们跟你一样无聊
Because they're very boring, like you
我告诉他们我不怎么管事了 他们应该找你
I told them I'm mostly out and they should meet you
一点也不好笑 伊姆兰
It's not funny, lmran
听着
Listen
嗯?
Hmm?
我爱你
I love you
我知道
I know
呵呵呵笑什么呢 小屁孩
What's so hehehe, kiddo,
你就没跟某个女孩说过我爱你吗?
you never said I love you to a girl before?
我的孩子...
My baby...
我当年才19岁
I was 19 years old,
我嫁给你父亲 飘扬过海来到这里后
when I married your father and came from India
我才知道
Until then I had learnt,
一个女孩从娘家嫁出来 和她丈夫成了家
that a girl goes from her father's home to her husband's,
就开始了一种新生活
and that becomes her new life
你父亲是个好人
Your father was a very nice man,
但是我永远都没法爱上他
but I could never love him,
好长一段时间以来 我并没觉得缺了点什么
and for a long time I didn't feel like anything was missing
他忙着做生意 我忙着养育女儿
He was busy with his business and I was busy bringing up my daughter,
直到有一天
and then one day
我遇见了伊姆兰...
I met lmran...
那时候我就...
and that's when...
...你坠入了情网
...you fell in love
是 我坠入了情网
Yes, I fell in love
你那时才四岁 因此我克制住了...
You were four then that's why I stopped myself...
但是当你十二岁的时候
but when you turned twelve
我坚持不下去了
I gave up
跟伊姆兰走了
and I went away with lmran
那时候我才明白一件事
By then I understood one thing,
如果你自己不开心
if you aren't happy yourself,
你永远都没法使别人开心
you can never keep others happy...
永远
never
你知道吗...
You know...
当我告诉伊姆兰
When I told lmran
我不想再要孩子
I do not want another child other than you,
他微笑着跟我说 我们并不需要结婚
he smiled and said that we didn't need to get married,
他不需要一纸证明或者征得牧师的同意
that he didn't need a piece of paper or the consent of a priest,
才答应一辈子跟我在一起
to be with me for life
他疯了... 就像我一样
He's crazy... just like me,
那可能也是我们需要彼此扶持
that's probably why we can't survive
才能活下去的原因
without each other
这么多年来我只知道恨你
For all these years I've only hated you
本来就是我的错...
But the fault was also mine...
不...
No...
不是你的错
it wasn't your fault
一个十二岁的女孩没法懂这一点
A 12-year-old girl could not understand this,
但我都二十一岁了
but a 21-year-old girl can,
我能理解你...
that what you did...
你的所作所为是完全正确的
was absolutely right
我真想你 妈妈
I missed you mama,
我好想你
I missed you so much
哦 你知道吗?
Oh, do you know,
打小以来我就希望有人能送我个这样的娃娃
since, childhood I've wished someone would give me a doll like this?
谢谢 波亚 非常感谢
Thank you, Pooja, thank you very much,
- 见到你真好 - 见到你真好
- Good to see you - Good to see you too
我带你去兜一圈怎么样?
Should I take you for a bike ride?
好啊 我们走
Come on, let's go
谢谢你
Thank you,
你把我妈妈照顾得这么好
you've given mama so much love
实际上我该谢谢你
I should actually thank you,
这么多年来
it's been many years,
我一直都靠插科打诨来填补你的空缺
that I've been clowning about, to make up for your absence,
但现在我可以退休了
but now I can retire
现在波亚都止不住笑
Now Pooja will never stop smiling
谢谢你能来 孩子 谢谢你
Thank you for coming my child, thank you
我能问你一件事吗?
Can I ask you one thing?
妈妈告诉我 虽然她没做任何承诺
Mama told me you waited eight years for her,
你等了她八年
without any promises
你怎么能那么确定...你们终将会在一起?
How were you so sure that...you would be together one day?
每段爱都有它的时机 当时时机并不成熟
Every love has its time. That time was not ours,
但不代表那不是爱
but that doesn't mean it wasn't love
我相信我的爱
I had faith in my love
在真爱面前 如果上帝都会屈服
If God can bow down in the face of love,
时间怎么可能取胜?
how does time stand a chance?
总会时来运转的
It had to change,
谢谢你 亲爱的
thank you darling,
谢谢你
thank you
- 伊姆兰 再见 - 拜拜
- Cheers Imran - Bye
我爱你
I love you
我知道
I know
来点咖啡吧
Coffee
我爱你
I love you,
我爱你 萨马
I love you Samar,
我爱你
I love you
你越界了 米拉
You're crossing the line, Meera
我爱你
I love you
# 只要你我的气息相伴 #
As my breath mingles with yours
# 我就仿若重获新生 #
I can breathe again
# 只要你我的气息相伴 #
As my breath mingles with yours
# 我就仿若重获新生 #
I can breathe again
# 你的体香直抵我的灵魂深处 #
The fragrance of your body touches my soul
# 如果你靠近 #
If you come near
# 我能自持住几时? #
How long can I control my senses?
# 何不任由感官跃动 #
Let them fly if they will
# 狂乱的心何时才能安分下来? #
When has the heart walked the straight and narrow?
# 何不任由心意徜徉 #
Let it wander if it will
# 深深地陷入对你的思念之中 #
Lost in thoughts of you
# 即便离群索居也能让我面带笑意 #
Solitude pleases me
# 只要你我的气息相伴 #
As my breath mingles with yours,
# 我就仿若重获新生 #
I can breathe again
# 是夜只要有你陪在身边 #
If the sweet night is spent by your side
# 次日必有和风阳光叩开拂晓的序幕 #
The dawn will break with light and air
# 只要我们四目相接 #
Since my eyes caught sight of you
# 我的眼里满满的只有你 #
They brim over with you alone
# 再次轻抚我 告诉我... #
Touch me again and tell me...
# ...你许下了什么心愿? #
...what did you wish for?
# 只要你我的气息相伴 #
As my breath mingles with yours
# 我就仿若重获新生 #
I can breathe again
# 你的体香直抵我的灵魂深处 #
The fragrance of your body touches my soul
# 如果你靠近 #
If you come near
# 我就仿若重获新生 #
I can breathe again
# 只要你靠近 #
If you come near
替我祝夏洛特生日快乐 附带一个吻
Wish Charlotte a happy birthday for me, with a kiss
我今天要跟爸爸坦白 他会同意的 是吧?
I am going to speak with papa today, he'll agree, won't he?
他会同意的 如果不同意 给我打电话
He'll agree, if he doesn't, call me
我会用一个吻来使他信服
I'll convince him with a kiss
我现在要走了 否则我就要因此失业了
I'm leaving now, or because of your papa I'll loose my job
听着 那我的...
Listen, what about mine...
米拉!!
Meera!!
我爱你
I love you
萨马!!
Samar!!
女士!
Madam!
女士 你不能过去
Madam you cannot go through
就一分钟...求你
Just give me one minute... please,
就一分钟...
just give me one minute...
就一分钟...你不明白...
just give me one minute...you don't understand...
你不能过去
You cannot come through here
请呆在这儿
Stay here please
拜托 拜托...
Please, please, please...
行行好吧 上帝!
please God!
拜托 拜托...
Please, please, please...
请不要这样
please don't do this,
请让他完好无损
please let him be okay,
不要因我的错而惩罚他
don't punish him for my mistake,
请让他活着吧
You keep him alive,
不遭受灾难 我保证
don't let anything happen to him and I promise,
我保证我再也不见他了
I promise I will never meet him,
求你了 上帝! 请让他完好无缺
please God! Let him be okay
我保证... 我保证...
I promise... I promise...
请让他活过来
Please bring him back
我向你保证我再也不会跟他见面
and I promise You I will never meet him again,
这件事过去之后我再也不会见他了
after this I will never meet him,
拜托 拜托 上帝
please, please, please, God
我将会永远离开他
I will leave him forever
先生
Sir
拜托 请让他活过来...
Please, bring him back...
好的 准备好了 电击!
Okay clear. Shock!
该死 我还是打不通米拉的电话
Shit ya, I still can't get through Meera's phone
四天了 她都没打过来 她也没来医院
For four days she hasn't called, nor did she come to the hospital
你觉得是不是她父亲对她大发雷霆了?
Do you think her father's upset with her,
你去店里找过她了吗?
did you find out from her store?
找过 保安说她也没去过
Yes, the guard was saying that she hasn't come there either,
我也不知道怎么回事
I don't know what the scene is
混蛋... 你真该去学学该怎么泡茶
Son of a... learn to make a simple cup of tea
朋友 再忍一周
My friend, adjust for one more week,
之后我就走了 你也喝不到我泡的茶了
after that neither will I be here, nor my tea
为什么 你不是在白金汉宫
Why, you've got a job
找到了一份保安的工作了吗?
at Buckingham Palace, as a guard?
没有 我要回拉合尔了
No, ya, I am going back to Lahore
我呆在伦敦 也没什么奔头
Nothing is going to happen for me in London
我靠你救济 继续找工作
Till when will I live off your money
这种生活什么时候是个头呀?
and keep looking for a job?
而且现在米拉也要来了...
And now Meera is also coming...
于是我给我妈妈打电话
so I called my mother
告诉她你儿子真没用...
and told her your son is useless...
他要回去了
he's coming back
想办法接受事实吧 还能怎么办?
Oh deal with it, what to do?
卡普尔叔叔 进来 不用见外
Kapoor Uncle, come in,think of it as your home,
哦 糟糕
oh shucks
米拉!
Meera!
啊 糟糕...
Ahh shucks...
我去... 买点茶 买点糖
I'll... get that tea, that sugar,
我去买点东西 你好啊 米拉
I'll get something. Hello Meera
- 拜 - 拜
- Bye - Bye
你爸爸不同意?
So papa didn't agree?
我没告诉他
I didn't speak with him
那你这些天在干什么?
So what were you doing all these days?
我在祈祷
I was praying
向耶稣大人祈祷吗?
To sir Jesus?
实现了吗?
Was it fulfilled?
当然了
Of course,
你祈求的是什么?
What did you ask for?
你的生命
Your life
作为回报 你放弃了什么?
And in return, what did you give up?
你!
You!
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
我祈祷说 无论如何 只要他能让你活下来
I prayed that He, by any means, keep you alive
作为回报 我将放弃一个对我来说
and in return, the one thing that is most precious to me,
最珍贵的东西
I will leave that,
永远
forever
你疯了吗?
You've gone mad?
萨马 拜托
Samar, please,
到这儿来看你已经够让我为难了
it's been very difficult for me to come here to you
我知道 你认为这些话就像是在胡扯
I realize that you think all this is rubbish,
你不会懂的
you won't understand,
但是这是我的信仰
but this is my belief,
你因为我的错而受到了惩罚
that you were punished for my faults,
如果我继续跟你在一起 你的生命...
that if I remain with you, your life...
没人能打破这种信仰
now no one can break this belief,
你不能 上帝也不能
neither you nor God
我来这只为告诉你
I have come here only to tell you
我要跟罗杰结婚了
that I am marrying Roger
还想要你答应我一件事...
I've come to ask you for one thing...
可能的话 请离开这座城市 远走高飞
that if possible, leave this city, and go away somewhere far,
拜托了...
please...
权当是为了我
for my sake
你没什么要说的吗?
You won't say anything?
祝贺你...
Congratulations...
一言为定
Done, done London
- 萨马 对不起... - 别...
- Samar, I'm sorry... - Don't...
别...
Don't...
呃 这是什么?
Uh, what's this?
给你妈妈打电话 告诉她 她儿子并非没用
Call your mother and tell her that her son is not useless,
他不会回去了
that he's not coming back
也告诉她 她的另外一个儿子要回印度
and also tell her that her other son is going back to India
请她为我祈祷
Ask her to pray for him
我把我所有的钱都留给了你 我要走了
I am leaving all my money for you and going
现在你可以用它做份大买卖
Now make something big out of it,
有一天我会回来拿我的那份的
I'll come back one day to take my share
我会很想念你的那杯茶的
I'll really miss that tea of yours,
你的朋友 萨马 再见
your friend, Samar, bye
事情不该这样
This isn't right,
都错了
it's all wrong,
彻底错了
completely wrong,
我和你正式开战
the war between you and me has begun
你把我的爱从我这里偷走了...
You stole my love from me...
我要从你那儿偷走她对你的信仰
I'll steal her belief from You
她相信如果我不跟她在一起
She believes if I am not with her
我就能活下去...
I will live...
所以从现在开始
So from now on,
我每天都要拥抱死亡
I will embrace death every day,
走着瞧吧...
Let's see...
你能让我活多久
till how long You keep me alive
谢谢你...
Thank you...
萨马・阿南德
Samar Anand
如果你是萨马的话 那就是说
If you're Samar that means,
米拉也是确有其人咯
there's also a Meera
你为什么不回去找她呢?
Why didn't you go back?
难道此后你再没见过米拉?
Didn't you meet Meera ever again?
听着 兵哥 这事我本不该插手
Look soldier, I shouldn't actually involve myself in this,
但显然我已无法置身事外了
but I am already involved now
你不认识我
You don't know me,
我可是个硬气的女孩
I'm a hardcore, kinda girl
从不轻易落泪
I never cry and all,
但是你的爱情故事深深地触动了我
but your love story made me fully sentimental
我二十一岁了
Look, I'm this 21 year old,
在这种随随便便和人上床
from this instant make out,
说分手就分手的时代
instant breakup generation
人们先上床 再考虑是否相爱
First we have sex and then we think if it was love or not
人们不懂爱情的本质
with these fundamentals of love there's solid confusion
兵哥 我想知道
Soldier, all I want to know is,
真爱确实存在吗?
is there such kind of love?
我是说
what I mean is,
要是它发生在了你身上
if it's happened to you
就可能发生在任何人身上
it could happen to anybody,
甚至是我?
maybe even me?
那么你告诉我
So tell me now,
这些到底是真的
was all this true or
还是只是你杜撰的消磨时间的故事?
just a story you wrote to pass time?
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
亚基拉!
Akira!
日本人?
From Japan?
德里人
Delhi
你挺有意思的...
You're cool...
就把它当作一个故事吧 别那么介怀
consider this a story and let it go
你会一如既往地那么硬朗...
you'll remain cool...
阿琼...
Arjun...
你爱我吗?
do you love me?
你愿意等我十年吗?
Can you wait ten years for me?
不行?
No?
那你就没机会了! 挂了吧!
Then you don't stand a chance!Put the phone down!
是你让我明白 兵哥
I give you this, soldier,
什么是真正的爱情!
if it's love it better be this way!
上半部完
至少给个机会让我试试吧
At least let me make a mock presentation,
你不会后悔的 求你了
you're not going to regret this,please let me do it
不! 不行! 亚基拉 我不同意
No! no! Akira, I can't allow it
求你了 凯瑟琳 这是绝好的机会
Please, Catherine,it's the chance of a lifetime
不行! 这太危险了!
No! It's too dangerous,
你经验不足
you don't have enough experience,
还是算了吧
so just forget it
大家伙注意 我们走
C'mon you lot, get a move on,
时间紧急 我们还得赶飞机
it's a wrap,we've got a flight to catch
求你了 凯瑟琳 我打小就梦想着...
Please, Catherine,this is my dream since I was a kid...
能为探索频道作报道... 旅行呀
to work for Discovery Channel...travel,
拍短片呀 冒险呀...
make films, features...
让我去吧
please let me do it
好吧
Alright,
给你两周时间 就两周!
two weeks, that's it!
你只能一个人去
And you'll be on your own,
拍摄和配音都由你自己来弄
you'll have to do the camera and the sound by yourself,
我可没承诺你任何事
and I'm making no promises
影片我要第一时间看
I get the first look at the footage
由我决定能不能上节目
and I get to decide if it's good enough for the channel
谢谢你!
Thank you!
离我远点 你这个疯女人!
Get off me, you mad woman!
我得去和纳塔拉詹将军谈谈
I'll speak to General Natarajan
伦敦! 伊拉克!
London! Iraq!
阿富汗!
Afghanistan!
墨西哥的毒品战!
Drug wars in Mexico!
世界啊...
The whole frigging world...
亚基拉来啦!
Here comes Akira!
帕哈干驻地 克什米尔地区
纳塔拉詹将军亲自打电话来了
General Natarajan called himself
这份文件将使印度军方大大受益
This documentary will benefit the Indian Army a lot
你知道为拆弹部队招募士兵有多困难
You know how difficult it is to recruit soldiers for the Bomb Squad
所以我觉得通过倾听你们的英勇事迹
So I felt that by hearing about stories of your bravery,
观摩你们的工作
by seeing you working,
会调动起年轻人的积极性
these youngsters will be motivated
激励他们向你们学习
and want to become like you
只有两周时间
and it's only a matter of two weeks,
感谢你的支持
I appreciate your support on this
长官
Sir
亚基拉・拉埃 来自探索频道
Akira Rai, Discovery Channel,
前来报到 长官
reporting for duty, sir
你偷的还是真的?
Is this stolen or for real?
我是个百分百的如假包换的士兵
It's a 100% authentic soldier,
这两周 我就是你的跟屁虫啦
now for two weeks,wherever you go, I go
你带了多少人来?
How many more have come to die with you?
就我自己 一个女兵
Just me, One Woman Crew
吃饭吧...
C'mon eat...
你好 我是卡马尔・辛格上尉
Hello, I'm Captain Kamal Singh
辛格长官!
Singh!
我是杰迪・德万上尉
And I'm Captain Jagdeep Dewan
德万长官!
Dewan!
哈里・克里斯南中尉 女士
Lieutenant Hari Krishnan, madam
别那么死板 不用非得叫我女士
You can stop this formality of calling me madam,
我叫亚基拉 就叫我亚基拉就行
I'm Akira, short and sweet Akira
你好 亚基拉!
Hello, Akira!
这样听着顺耳多了
Now that's perfect
接下来的两周 可能会有很多事情要麻烦你们
Now look, for the next two weeks I am going to trouble you a lot,
如果我说多了 或吃多了
so for speaking excessively,for eating excessively,
或者情绪失控
and for abusing uncontrollably,
先向你们请求原谅啦
I ask you'll to forgive me now
只有一点
I have one question,
希望你们不要像你们老大那样坏脾气
I just hope that you aren't as grumpy as your boss
不不不 我们脾气好着呢
No, no, not at all,we are very jolly guys
那么 我们会相处的很愉快的 伙计们
Then I am afraid we are going to have a lot of fun, guys
问下 我把行李放在哪里?
By the way,where do I dump this stuff?
跟我来 跟我来
I will show you, I will show you
保持一定距离
Make sure the distance is maintained,
亚基拉・拉埃小姐
Miss Akira Rai
亚基拉・拉埃 报到 长官
Akira Rai reporting for duty, sir
丰富多彩的军旅生活还真是让人激动呢
This action-packed army life is really exciting
你必须呆在隔离带后面
You will always remain behind this barricade,
我身后350米
and 350 metres behind me
要是你违反纪律
If you break any rule
就会被送回营房 还有疑问吗?
you'll be sent back to the barracks, any doubts?
那我能听音乐吗?
Can I listen to music on my Ipod?
能还是不能啊?
Is that a yes or no?
天啊
Oh man
菊链结构啊...
Daisy Chain uh...
菊链：也称总线拓扑 在这种结构中所有节点都连接到并行的电缆上
是 长官
Yes sir
拔掉弹头安全吗?
Safe to disable cap?
是 长官 我检查过了
Yes sir, I've checked it
我认为 很可能有另外的引爆装置 德万
I think there might be another switch Dewan
有可能
Quite possible
一个一个来
In sequence
切断弹头
Cut cap
按顺序来
Go in sequence
是 长官
Okay sir
这是连到哪里的?
Where is this going?
不知道 长官
No idea sir
我来看看
Let me check this
把座椅调低
Lowering seat
是 长官
Okay sir
这有个引爆装置 德万
There's a switch Dewan
小心点 长官
Be careful sir
亚基拉!!
Akira!!
你还好么?
Are you okay?
你以为我们在干什么 拍电影?
What did you think was going on, some film shoot,
还是探险之旅
or some kind of adventure trip,
好让你回家去四处炫耀?
that you'll go home and show off to your friends?
我们是在和他妈的炸弹打交道
We are dealing with bloody bombs here
今天 就因为你
Today, because of you,
我手下的全体队员都有性命之忧
the lives of my entire team was compromised
对不起
I'm sorry
我都说了350米
350 metres I said
现在你别跟着我们了 你赶紧回去吧
Now you will not come with us,you'll go back from here
不 兵哥 我不回去 我跟你们一起去
No, soldier, I am not going back,I am coming with you
前路危险重重 你应付不了的
The road ahead is dangerous,you will not be able to manage
兵哥 我这辈子全靠这次机会了
Soldier, this is my life's one and only chance,
没啥我克服不了的困难
I'll cope with anything
求你了 对不起
Please, I am sorry
亚基拉!
Akira!
听着 你是个好女孩 你也很勇敢
Look, you're an okay  girl,you're brave too,
但是这工作没有番训练
but this is not possible
真的不好应付 男女都一样
for untrained girls or boys
听我的... 别瞎想了
Listen to me and... forget this story
换成是我让你忘了米拉 你能做得到吗?
If I asked you to forget Meera,will you forget her?
人一生中总得有点追求吧
There is always this one passion,that a person has
对你来说是米拉
for you it's Meera,
对我来说 就是你的故事
for me my passion is your story,
我不走!
I'm not going!
对不起
Sorry
克里斯南  ! 长官会去哪里?
Oh Krishnan! Where is sir going?
他在排爆后 总会独处一会
Sir always goes for some quiet time after defusing a bomb
安静!
Quiet!
哦 亚基拉 劝你别去惹熟睡的狮子
O Akira, never mess around with a lion that's sleeping
辛格 我可不是来拍鸟的
O Singh, I haven't come here to shoot birds,
我就是来拍狮子的
I've come here to shoot the Lion
尤其是这只狮子
And this Lion I will shoot for sure
- 德万  - 在
- Dewan - Yes
继续煮鸡汤 我去去就来
Keep the chicken cooking,I'll be back in a bit
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 亦曾欣喜 亦曾悲伤 #
Wanders with a smile...
# 他只身流浪 #
...and a tear
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 处处为家 #
Belonging to all
# 又处处无家 #
Yet none to call my own
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
你白天敢与炸弹厮混
You play around with bombs in the day,
晚上会唱着浪漫的歌曲
and sing romantic songs by night
让我怎能不爱上你啊?
How is it possible not to fall in love with you?
等着瞧吧
You wait,
不出两周 你就会给亚基拉唱旁遮普民歌了吧
in two weeks you will sing Punjabi songs for Akira,
这就是我挑战
this is my challenge,
晚安 帅哥
good night, sexy
真他...
What the...
对不起...球拿来
Sorry... ball
扎尔
Afzal
唉 倒霉 摄像机坏了
Oh shucks, the camera broke
不行 亚基拉 不能用了
No ya, Akira, now this will not work,
在扎莫连配件都买不到
and we won't get these parts even in Jammu,
只能拿回德里修了
this can be fixed only in Delhi
对不起 亚基拉 我...我...
I'm sorry, Akira I'm... I'm...
没事的 克里斯南   不是你的错
Hey it's okay,Krishnan, it's not your fault
见识到我那梅西式的射门技术
After seeing my Messi like kick,
惊得丢掉摄像机也是很正常的
anybody would have dropped the camera,
探索频道怎么会选用我拍摄的东西呢?
and in any case where was Discovery Channel going to take me?
我哪里还有什么机会
It was just a one-off chance I was taking
晚安吧
Okay good night
兵哥
Soldier,
不用再麻烦你招待亚基拉啦
Akira's entertainment was only till here,
明早我就走了 回德里
tomorrow morning it's about-turn,back to Delhi,
你终于可以摆脱我了
finally you get rid of me,
现在 至少给我来个媚笑吧
at least now give me one sexy smile
无所谓了 你还是那么个脾气
Fine then, remain grumpy
亚基拉 至少吃点东西
Oye, Akira, at least eat your food
不了 辛格 我不饿
No ya, Singh, I'm not hungry
你们俩都得吃点
Both of you'll eat
不吃了 长官
No sir
不吃算了
Fine don't eat
亚基拉! 微笑...
Akira! Smile...
现在大家看到的是
And now we have
来自探索频道的奥斯卡最佳微笑获得者
Discovery Channel's Oscar-winning
制作人亚基拉・拉埃小姐
film-maker miss Akira Rai,
跟你的粉丝们说点什么吧...
a few words for your fans...
嘿! 怎么修好的?
Hey! How is it fixed?
萨马修的 他精通电子设备
Samar did it,he's an electronics genius,
他修了一晚上
he worked all night on it
他在哪?
Where's that genius?
你这人怎么这么复杂?
Why are you so complicated?
让人又爱又恨
Neither can one fully hate you nor love you
现在我才明白
Actually I've understood now,
你看了我的泳装造型 就回心转意啦
after seeing me in my swimsuit,you've changed your mind,
觉得我很性感 是吧?
now I've started looking hot to you, right?
别这么盯着我 兵哥
Don't give me such intense looks, soldier,
让我感觉怪怪的
it fills me with this weird kind of sensation
你再废话连篇 我就去把摄像机砸了
Stop talking rubbish or I'll break the camera again
你先回答我...
First tell me...
为什么要忙一晚上帮我修摄像机?
why did you stay up all night and fix my camera?
你说到过追求
You spoke about passion
要是有人热衷某物又偏偏得不到
When someone is passionate about something and doesn't get it,
他会不惜倾其一生苦苦追寻
he spends a lifetime going mad chasing it
就像你眼前的这个癫狂的我
There's one mad man standing in front of you,
我不希望你也变成我这样
there is no place here for another mad person,
所以 拿着你的摄像机去完成心愿吧 走吧
so pick your camera,fulfill your passion and leave
随便你怎么说 你阻止不了我的
Try as hard as you can,you won't save me from going mad
靠近我一点 再往前来点
Towards me, more towards me
干得好
Nice, nice
再来点 再来点
A little bit, a little bit
让我看看这设备
Let me see the device
好
Yup
就在这!
Exactly!
怎么了 德万?
What's happened, Dewan?
大桥中央发现了炸弹
Sir, it's bang in the centre of the bridge
带计时器?
Any timer?
炸药与计时器通过电线相连
Yes, sir, and the wires go to the dynamite through the relay
电线缠绕在装炸药的罐子外面
They're wrapped around cans filled with Anfo
知道了
Ya
哎 大记者
Oye Kurusawa,
是时候实现你的梦想了
come fulfill your passion
太棒了!
Wow great!
你不怕?
You're not scared?
我身边这位可是"不死传奇"呢
I'm hanging here with 'The man who cannot die',
货真价实!
Literally!
我用不着害怕
There's no chance of being scared,
老大 你生来就是拆弹高手
your destiny is working on a strike rate of 100%, boss
我们这种工作 一次失手就在劫难逃
In our line of work destiny betrays you just once
别怕 不会是今天
Don't worry, today's not that day,
因为我可不想这么快就死
'cause I have no plans of dying so quickly
我还要做很多纪录片呢
I have to make many more documentaries
让全世界都看到
and show them in every country in the world,
我还要跟世界各地的帅哥上床
I have to have sex with guys with different accents
你是读着性爱圣经长大的吗?
Did you grow up reading the Kama Sutra?
满脑子里都是这些东西?
Is this all you think of?
兵哥 我这个年龄段的人就这样
Soldier, at my age,this is all we think of
我长到你那么大时 才会思考到底什么是爱
When I grow older like you,I'll start thinking of love,
做一个好市民 以及朝圣之类的 明白?
being a good citizen,the ways of God, okay?
随便
Okay
顺便问下 兵哥
By the way, soldier,
你这辈子就只爱米拉一个吗?
do you plan on being in love with Meera all your life,
你还有没有可能爱上别人?
or is there a chance for someone else in between?
我忽然想到个好主意 你想知道吗?
There's a mind blowing offer,do you want to hear it?
我有的选吗?
Is there a choice?
没有
No
让我当你的女朋友吧
Make me your girlfriend
为什么?
Why?
我年轻... 幽默... 又性感
I'm young... I'm entertaining...I'm sexy,
你已经见识过我的身材了
you've already checked my body out,
事实上 我是你的无上之选
actually I'm like a jackpot for you
机会仅此一次... 考虑下啦
it's a limited offer... think about it
兵哥 兵哥 听着...
Soldier, soldier, listen...
我从未向上帝祈求过什么
I never ask God for anything,
我的承诺仅此一点
so by making promises and all
我绝不要离开你
and leaving you is out of the question
我把你逗笑了 你是我的人啦
I made you laugh, you're mine now
# 我带着梦想的翅膀飞离 #
Away I go, carried on wings of passion
# 啜饮时间的甘露 #
Drinking droplets of time
# 心已飞出牢笼 #
My heart has flown from its cage
#　爱上这样的自己 #
Falling in love with myself
# 张开双臂拥抱生活 #
Embracing life with open arms
# 我带着梦想的翅膀飞离 #
Away I go, carried on wings of passion
# 心已飞出牢笼 #
My heart has flown from its cage
# 爱上这样的自己 #
Falling in love with myself
# 张开双臂拥抱生活 #
Embracing life with open arms
# 像只蝴蝶掠过你的指尖 #
Clasping the moment in your fingertips like a butterfly
# 舞动的双翼留下多彩的痕迹 #
As it takes wing it leaves traces of colour
# 时间如流水般蜿蜒前行 #
The moment moves on,
# 远远抛下曾经的斑斓 亚基拉 #
leaving its colour behind, Akira
# 任时光流转 要把握住下一个瞬间 #
I clasp another moment as it takes flight
# 张开双臂拥抱生活 #
Embracing life with open arms
# 我带着梦想的翅膀飞离 #
Away I go,carried on wings of passion
# 心已冲出牢笼 #
My heart has flown from its cage
# 爱上这样的自己 #
Falling in love with myself
# 张开双臂拥抱生活 #
Embracing life with open arms
萨马・阿南德少校
So Major Samar Anand,
此行的最后一个问题
the last question of our trip,
怎么你从来都不穿防爆服?
why haven't you worn a bomb suit till now?
呃...
Um...
防爆服是为了能让你远离危险
Bomb suits are meant to protect you from danger,
远离伤害 伤痛
to protect you from getting hurt, or being wounded,
但能伤到你的不是炸弹 而是生活
but more than bombs it's life, that hurts you,
每个角落都上演着背叛 痛苦...
at every corner there's betrayal, some pain...
如果不穿防爆服能把我们从困境中解救出来
so if we don't wear bomb suits to save us from the dangers of life,
穿着它徒然求生又有什么意义?
what's the point of wearing it to save us from death?
生活一天天地将我们消磨
Every day, life kills us a little,
炸弹才能让你一了百了
a bomb will kill us just once
好了 兵哥 完事啦
Okay soldier, that's a wrap,
影片拍好了 也不用再折磨你了
the end of my film and your torture
你这是在打量我吗?
Are you checking me out?
我在想以前对你的看法是多么的错误
I was thinking how wrong I was about you
我以前认为你熬不过两天的
I'd thought that you wouldn't last more than two days with us,
但你却是个真正的强者
but you turned to be really tough boss
你以前有问过我的事吗?
Have you ever asked me anything about myself?
你总是这副抓狂的表情
All you gave were intense angry looks
我是国家级游泳运动员 州级网球运动员
I'm a national level swimmer, a state level tennis player,
我四分钟可以跑一千米
I can run a kilometer in four minutes,
我还是名深海潜水员
I'm a deep sea diver,
基本上我是超女啦 什么事我都能做到
basically I'm Super Girl, make me do anything
就没有你做不到的事吗?
So, there's nothing that you can't do?
还真有件
There's one thing
什么?
What?
我无法让你爱上我
I couldn't make you fall for me
真是 你又开始说笑了
There, you've started again
我已经爱上你了 萨马
I'm in love with you, Samar
完全地 彻底地 疯狂地
Totally, completely, madly,
亚基拉已深深地爱上了你
Akira has fallen flat in love with you
你没必要说什么
There's no need to say anything,
我知道你对我完全没有兴趣
I know you're not at all interested,
这... 没事啦
and it's... it's totally cool
迄今为止 都是男生围着我转
Until now, boys have always run after me,
我从未主动过
I've never run after anybody,
你很特别
but you're this special piece, ya
同龄人中 我再也找不到一个像你这样的情人
In my generation I'll never find a lover like you,
我既然遇见了你
and now that I've met you,
就无力再爱上别人
I can't love someone lesser than you,
换句话说 芳心彻底被你俘获啦 大佬
so basically, I'm screwed, boss
你说话的口气和我一样
You deliver dialogues just like me,
只是...
just...
不要像我那样为爱痴狂...
don't end up falling in love like me...
因为如果你的笑容不再
because if your laughter,
也不再耍小性子 不再吵闹
this mischief, this abusive language, stops,
这世界就更无趣了
this world will surely lose something
怎么会哭呢?
Where do these come from?
克里斯南  !
Krishnan!
再会 亚基拉
See you, Akira
德万!
Dewan!
再见 辛格
Bye Singh
保重 亚基拉
Take care, Akira
别担心 我不会哭的
Don't worry, I'm not going to cry
我知道 你可是超女呢
Ya ya, I know, you're super girl
那是
That I am
照顾好自己
Take care of yourself,
别死掉了
don't die or anything like that
要不然我们就真成悲惨爱情故事了
ours is going to be a deadly love story
你不要因我而改变
You're not going to change
太晚了
There's no chance
我可不要友谊式的拥抱
I don't want these friendly hugs,
如果你要亲我 那就来吧
if you want to kiss me, then do that
这算吻吗?
This was a kiss?
那是战友间的亲吻
That's how the army's taught us
等着我
You wait,
等我回来 给你展示什么才是真正的亲吻
Iet me come back, and show you how to kiss for real
真的?
Really?
再会...
I'll see you...
好啦 我们一小时后还要赶去巴拉穆拉
Come on, we have to reach Baramullah in one hour
别让自己情绪失控
control your emotions
否则就无法胜任排爆工作了
otherwise the bomb will be out of control
如果不穿防爆服能把我们从困境解救中出来
So if we don't wear bomb suits to save us from the dangers of life,
穿着它徒然求生又有什么意义?
what's the point of wearing it to save us from death?
生活一天天地将我们消磨
every day, life kills us a little,
炸弹才能让你一了百了
a bomb will kill us just once
你把我这种铁石心肠的人都感动哭了!
You made the bitch cry!
大爱呀!
I love it!
我保证他们会把这播出去
I'm going to make sure they run this
你个蠢货在我改变主意之前赶紧滚开
Get off me you stupid girl before I change my mind
我们会将它命名为"不死传奇"
We are going to title it 'The Man Who Cannot Die'
我要把它排在九月版的头条
I want it to be the lead for the September issue,
亚基拉 让他搭个航班
so Akira, put him on a flight
尽快把他带到伦敦
and get him to London as soon as possible,
上层想要证实他故事的真实性
the big boys will want to authenticate his story
他一定得亲自过来吗?
Does he have to come here for that?
我是说 我们不能就在他的驻地完成吗?
I mean, can't we just do this there?
因为你是新手 不能 就把他带过来
For a story done by a rookie, no, just get him here
他是不会来的
He won't come!
怎么会不来?
Why the hell not?
他就是不会
He just won't
听着 虽然我不是老板
Listen girl, I don't run this company
但是我保证要是他不来的话
but I do know that if he doesn't get his arse over here,
你的报道就只能被束之高阁了
your story stays in the edit room,
给你二十四小时 带他来见我
you've got 24 hours to get back to me
上帝保佑吧!
In the name of God!
兵哥 他们看了纪录片 被打动了
Soldier, they've flipped it after seeing your story,
他们想把它做成九月版的主打故事
they want to make it the cover story for the September issue
还答应和我签约 起薪二万五千英镑啊
and sign me for a starting salary of 25 thousand quid
为期三年
and a three-3 year contract
恭喜 超女
Okay congratulations, super girl
我死之前 你还让我火了一把啊
you made me famous before I died
但是 兵哥...
But soldier...
有个小问题
there's a small... problem
你能有什么问题?
What problem can you have?
问题就是那个报道 签约
The problem is that this story, this contract,
这些 前提是你要来次伦敦
all this, will happen only if you come to London
这是我第一份报道 我是新人
This is my first story and I'm new,
所以这是他们约定俗成的惯例
so it's their system it can't be changed
就一天啦 兵哥
It's only for one day, soldier,
我保证 二十四个小时后你就又回印度了
in twenty- four hours you'll be back in lndia, I promise
我知道你也挺为难的
I know it's not easy for you,
但这是我人生的转折点
but my life is at stake here,
这会让我事业至少快进五年
my career will get at least a 5 year kick start,
求求你啦 兵哥哥 就为我!
please soldier, for me!
我去不了!
I can't come!
抱歉 亚基拉!
Sorry Akira!
没事的
It's okay
他个混蛋!
What an arsehole!
他不是混蛋 约翰
He's not an arsehole, John
那是怎么回事?
So what's his problem then?
他只是... 有烦心事 说来话长啦
He's just... messed up, it's a long story
那你要回去吗?
Are you heading back?
是呀
Ya, I mean,
这一周来 凯瑟琳一直在尝试说服领导们
it's been a week since Catherine's been trying to convince the bosses,
但是... 没用呀
but... it's not working,
所以我猜我要回德里去了
so I guess I'm back to Delhi's belly
真是个混蛋!
What an arsehole!
喂?
Hello?
你们这探索频道是有多少办公室呀?
How many offices do these Discovery Channel guys have?
我这有个岔路 真不知道要往哪边走
I am standing at a cross road, I can't understand where to go
你在哪?
Where are you?
探索频道办公室附近
I am standing somewhere near the Discovery Channel office,
这些房子看起来没啥区别
all the buildings look the same
你 就在那等着 我马上来
You, you wait right there, I'm coming
他... 来... 啦!
He... is... here!
我就说他不是混蛋吧
I told you he is not an arsehole
抱歉
Sorry
谢谢你 兵哥 谢谢
Thank you soldier, thank you,
太谢谢啦 兵哥哥
Thank you soldier,
我知道 你能来伦敦真是不容易
it's a big deal that you've come to London, I know this,
你能为我而来 真是我人生中的幸事
but that you've come here for me is the biggest thing in my life
别在这自恋了 我又不是为你而来
Don't get sentimental, I haven't come for you,
我就顺便来看看你
I've come to set you here, permanently,
然后我能永远地摆脱你了
so that I'm free from you for forever
休想 兵哥
No chance, soldier,
以前这故事只是一厢情愿
so far this story has been one - sided,
现在看来又有新转机啦
now it looks like there's going to be a twist in the story
亚基拉!!
Akira!!
让下 让下
Move, move
萨马 萨马 你能听见我吗
Samar, Samar, can you hear me,
萨马... 你是医生吗?
Samar... are you a doctor?
拜托帮忙联系医生 好吗?
Can someone please call a doctor?
拜托帮忙叫下救护车 好吗?
Can someone please call an ambulance?
萨马 萨马 萨马
Samar, Samar, Samar,
我该怎么办?
What do I do?
萨马!
Samar!
醒醒 打扰下 他想见你
Excuse me, sorry he's asking for you
米拉在哪?
Where's Meera?
没事了 萨马
It's okay, Samar
你能帮我叫下米拉...
Can you call Meera please...
那个护士说她在外面等我
the other nurse said she is waiting outside for me...
你可以帮我叫她... 帮我叫她过来
Will you call her... will you call her please
护士... 你能帮我叫米拉过来吗?
Nurse... will you please call Meera?
你刚说她在外面等我
you said she is waiting for me...
我... 我现在就要见她
I...... I need to see her now...
你怎么不凑近一点?
Why aren't you going to him?
我要见她
I need to see her
我不是米拉!
I'm not Meera!
怎么了!
What's wrong!
怎么你们不去叫 米拉?
Why aren't you calling Meera?
去叫汗医生
Go get Dr. Khan
她没事吧?
Is she okay?
她是不是出事了?
Has something happened to her?
怎么你们都不说话?
Why aren't you saying something?
拜托了 我...
please, l...
帮我去叫米拉
Call Meera please
我要见她
I need to see Meera
早上好 萨马!
Good morning, Samar!
我是佐雅・阿里・汗医生
I'm Dr. Zoya Ali Khan,
昨晚是我为你做的手术
Last night I operated on you,
你现在感觉怎么样了?
how are you feeling now?
嗯
Hmm
全名?
Full name?
萨马・阿南德
Samar Anand
年龄?
Age?
二十八岁
28 years
今年是哪一年 萨马?
What year are we in, Samar?
2002年
在这之前萨马有发生过意外
Has Samar been in an accident
或遭受过严重创伤吗?
or gone through serious trauma before this?
十年前有过一次车祸 就在伦敦...
10 years ago there was an accident... here in London...
这是那次车祸后第一次回来
after that he's come back to London for the first time
那就说得通了
That explains it,
萨马患的是逆行性遗忘
Samar is suffering from retrograde amnesia
他的记忆倒退了十年
he has regressed ten years,
他的记忆 停留在了2002年
his memory, is stuck in the year 2002
这次车祸所造成的创伤
the trauma of this accident has
使他的记忆倒退到上次的车祸
regressed his memory to the previous accident,
他记得那车祸之前的所有事
he remembers everything up until the previous accident,
但是之后的事他就没有印象了
but after that he remembers nothing
那他会... 会康复的 对吧?
But he'll... become okay, won't he?
像这种情况 很难说
In cases like these, it's impossible to say,
有些患者在一天后就恢复记忆 但有些...
some patients get their memory back in a day and for some...
永远无法恢复!
never!
那 现在怎么办?
So... now?
首先我们要找来他以前认识的人
Firstly we will have to bring in the people he knew
当他和自己信任的人在一起时
when he is with the people he trusts,
会同时缓解他的紧张感与精神创伤
his shock and trauma will both lessen
那样也许我们能把他的记忆找回来
and then we might be able to bring him back
这是萨马提供的一些名字 地址和电话号码
These are some names, addresses and numbers, Samar has given,
我不知道这些是否仍然有效
I don't know if these are still valid,
但要是你尽量多找几个 总会有用...
but if you find as many as possible, it will help...
对了 这女孩是关键
and yes, the most important is this girl,
米拉!
Meera!
萨马从昨天开始就一直在找她
Samar's been asking for her, since yesterday
兵哥哥呀
Aye soldier,
怎么会那么戏剧化 就只把我忘了?
why so much drama, just to forget me?
但是现在你听着
but now you listen,
随你怎样
do what you want,
亚基拉是不会让你忘记她的
Akira won't let you forget her
宝贝 宝贝 看镜头
Honey, honey look into the camera
你们真漂亮
You look beautiful
嗨 爸爸
Hi daddy
嗨...
Hi...
米拉!
Meera!
啊?
Yes?
我要跟你谈谈...
I need to talk to you...
抱歉 我... 好像不认识你吧
I'm sorry l... can't seem to place you
对 我们是没见过
No... ya... um we've never met...
我是亚基拉... 几分钟就好
I'm Akira... I just need a few minutes
我真的是开会要迟到了
You know I'm extremely late for a meeting,
真是抱歉
I'm really sorry,
麻烦你先跟我的助理预约一下吧...
but would you mind making an appointment with my assistant...
真是抱歉!
I'm really sorry!
是关于萨马!
It's about Samar!
我知道你有难处...
I know how difficult this is for you...
你有幸福的家庭... 有丈夫...
you have a family... a husband...
还有女儿...
a daughter...
但是他除了你 一无所有
but beside you, there's no one else who can do this
萨马一直在找你
Samar keeps asking for you,
他就是想见你
he only wants to see you
医生觉得要是他能见你一次
The doctor feels if he see's you just once,
看到你 他也许能接受事实...
meets you, he might be able to hear the truth...
就一次 米拉...
just come once, Meera...
求求你了...
please...
为了萨马...
for Samar...
米拉 和萨马谈话你要特别注意
Meera, you'll have to handle Samar very carefully,
他的精神状态不稳定
his mental state is very delicate,
任何震惊或坏消息对他来说
any kind of shock or bad news
可能都是种永久伤害
could permanently damage his system
这样就更难以把他带回现实了
and then bringing him back may be impossible
还有米拉 要记住...
and Meera, just remember...
你是萨马通往外界的桥梁
you are the bridge that joins Samar to the outside world
准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
可以开始了吗?
Shall we do this?
很好!
Great!
我先去看看他 再叫你
I'll just check on him and call you
谢谢!
Thank you!
# 有你的身影浮现在我眼中 #
Seeing you makes me feel
# 远去的梦境再次重现 #
A departed dream returns to me
# 度过了如世纪般漫长的夜晚 #
Passing through that century-long night
# 清晨的曙光突现在我的眼帘 #
A burst of morning returns to me
# 神采飞扬 翻山越岭 #
Keeping awake, crossing miles
# 魂牵梦绕 #
The dream held me by the hand
# 我沉寂了这些许年月 #
Breath held for many years
# 如今终又重获新生 #
I can breathe again
# 只要你我的气息相生相伴 #
As my breath mingles with yours
# 我就仿若重获新生 #
I can breathe again
萨马 在车祸前你记得最后一件事是什么?
Samar, what's the last thing you remember before the accident?
米拉...
Meera...
米拉穿了件性感的粉色裙子...
Meera is dressed in a sexy pink dress...
披着头发...
her hair is open...
她微笑着... 看我表演摩托特技
she's smiling... watching me do stunts on my bike,
突然一辆车撞向我 然后...
and then suddenly a car slams into me and then...
眼前一片漆黑!
Black!
整个世界都是如此!
Full black!
萨马 你刚说的车祸发生在十年前
Samar, the accident you are talking about happened ten years ago
现在不是2002年 现在是2012年
and we're not in 2002, we are in the year 2012
什么!
What!
米拉... 这... ?
Meera... this... ?
萨马!
Samar!
先听她说
Just listen to her
我来解释一下
Let me explain,
萨马你因头部受伤而导致部分记忆缺失
Samar because of the head injury you have amnesia,
逆行性遗忘
Retrograde amnesia
这在头部创伤中非常常见
and it is very common with head injuries
所以别担心
so please don't worry,
随着时间的推移 你会慢慢记起一切
with time you will remember everything,
你会完全康复的
and you will become absolutely okay
我知道你有很多疑问
I know you have a lot of questions that you want answers for
米拉会陪着你
Meera is with you
有需要就随时叫我 我就在外面 好吗?
and whenever you need me. I'm right outside, okay?
待会见
I'll see you
我无法理解 米拉...
I don't understand, Meera...
十年了...
10 years...
已经十年了!
10 years!!
萨马 没事的...
Samar It's ok...
没事的...
it's ok...
我们在一起十年了?
We've been together for 10 years?
我们结婚多久了?
How long have we been married?
五年
Five years
我想要记起每件事..
I want to remember everything...
记起和你一起度过的每分每秒...
everyday, every second I've spent with you...
我想要记起所有的事...
I want to remember everything...
我... 我想记起所有的事...
I... I want to remember everything...
不 米拉 可以了...
No, ya Meera, no more...
你已经做了很多了
you've already done so much and
要你再花时间
to ask you for more of your time,
在这些事情上
to do all this drama
我觉得心里有愧
I don't feel right
你有你的家庭 你老公 还有女儿
you have a family, a husband, a daughter
亚基拉...
Akira...
我没结婚
I'm not married
我也没有女儿...
And nor do I have any daughter...
我许诺离开萨马
I made a promise to leave Samar,
不是去结婚...
not to get married...
罗杰是老朋友了 一生一世的老朋友
Roger is an old friend and has always remained a friend
他离婚了 所以...
He is divorced so...
我每年都帮他安排他女儿的生日派对
every year I help him arrange his daughter's birthday
我不忍心看到萨马这样
I can't bear to see Samar like this,
我想尽我所能去帮他
and I want to do whatever I can,
但是我要先告诉你
but before that, it was necessary for me to tell you this
我爱萨马 亚基拉
I love Samar, Akira,
以前爱他 以后也会一直爱他
always have, always will,
但我永远不能和他在一起
but I can never be his
现在你都知道了
Now after knowing all this,
你要做什么...
what needs to be done...
全凭你决定
is up to you
萨马说得对
Samar was right,
我听了他的爱情故事 就该一笑置之
I should have left his love story as just a story and forgotten about it
我以前不这么感情用事...
I was cool...
我应该一直保持原样...
I would've remained cool,
但我爱他爱得太深 怎能随便放弃
but I got trapped in his love so much, now I can't let it go
来吧... 我们先接他出院
Come... let's get him back
然后再一起帮他找回记忆吧
and then beat him up together,
来瓶上好的智利红酒?
A nice bottle of Chilean Red?
当然...
Definitely, ya sure...
一切都好么 先生?
Is everything alright sir?
是的 很好 谢谢
Yes very well thank you
好的
Okay,
都还好么 夫人?
All okay ma'am?
嗯 谢谢
Hmm Thank you
玛利亚 史密斯夫人已经等了45分钟了
Maria, Mrs. Smith has been waiting for 45 minutes
如果她要吃玛利亚特别料理
If she's asked for Maria's special of the day
她就得花点时间等着
then she will have to wait for it to be special,
走开 别烦我了
now leave me alone
好吧 这就是跟一个白人结婚的...
Superb, here's getting married to a white...
米拉...
Meera...
扎因 如果你不愿意做的话就直说吧
Zain, if you can't do this feel free to say so,
我们知道这些要求可能太过分了
we realize that we're probably asking for a bit too much
过分?
Too much?
不 亚基拉 你们一点也不过分
No, Akira, you're asking for too little
这个餐厅 我的房子都是萨马的
This restaurant, my house all of it is Samar's
我是用他给我的钱开始创业的
... I started all this with the money that he gave me,
不然我这个拉合尔人怎么可能有这些成就?
otherwise how would this Lahori have done all this?
他告诉过我有一天他会来要他的那一份
He told me that he'd come one day to take his share
可不应该是这种方式...
but not like this...
你们别担心
You'll don't worry,
玛利亚和我会搬去温布利的老房子
Maria and I will shift into our old Wembley flat
餐厅 房子从现在起就是萨马的了
The restaurant, the house is all Samar's from now,
只要告诉我你们什么时候带他来
just tell me when are you bringing him
明天...
Tomorrow...
就像萨马以前说的那样 一言为定
So as Samar used to say, done, done, London...
一言为定
Done, done, London...
谢谢你 扎因
Thank you, Zain
不客气
Oh never mind
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
伦敦...
London...
我们一年年老去 这座城市却越来越年轻
we're growing older but this city is getting younger
你怎么说的来着...
What were you saying...
我们有自己的餐厅?
we have our own restaurant?
是的 先生! 叫萨马之家
Yes, sir! Samar's Kitchen,
属于伦敦十大最佳餐厅之一
it's amongst the top 10 restaurants in London
我从来没想过 我们会有自己的餐厅
I'd never imagined, that we'd have our own restaurant,
小屋 还有车...
a bungalow, a car...
可能是上帝一不小心对我们太好了
Accidently God's been too kind. I think
所以他现在要拿点什么走
that's why He's making things even now
是啊 不过他只是想让你休息一下 别多想
Oye, He is letting you rest for a while, nothing else
不要太情绪化了 不然我们又要出意外了
Don't get too emotional or we'll meet with another accident
其他的我都能理解
Everything else I can understand
只有一件事我很纳闷
One thing I can't understand,
你是怎么勾搭上玛利亚的?
is how did you hook Maria?
巴帕帅...巴基斯坦的帕坦人的魅力
PPK... Pakistani Pathan's charisma
所以你现在是"拉合尔之光"了
So now Lahore's famous because of you
到了 我们到家了
Here you go, we've come home
米拉 好好照顾你的宝贝
Meera, here, take care of your prized possession,
我和玛利亚明天再来... 拜拜
I will come with Maria tomorrow... bye
现在你不管耶稣大人了
Now you've left Sir Jesus
开始转拜克里希纳神了...
and you're making deals with Shree Krishna...
克里希纳：印度主神之一 意译为“黑天”
不然我怎么办啊
So what should I do,
如果你再出意外怎么办?
if you meet with one accident after another?
我得让各路神灵都高兴啊
I'll have to, keep all the Gods happy
不会再有意外了 我保证 好吧
No more accident's, I promise okay
来 老婆 带我看看我的家
Come, my wife, show me my home
就我们俩住这么大个房子
We live alone in such a big house,
还是与其他人合住啊?
or is there someone else on rent here?
哇哦
Wow
我们中过彩票么?
Did we win a lottery?
耶稣大人还灵验吗?
How is sir Jesus doing?
你祈祷的事情现在如何?
How are the deals coming along?
我不再祈求什么了
I've stopped making deals and vows
我现在什么都不要
Now I don't ask for anything of anybody
为什么会这样呢?
Wow, how did this happen?
我有你
I got you,
我再无他求了
so there is no need to ask for anything else
你这么爱我?
You love me that much?
怎么了?
What?
汗医生说 这些天都不能...
Doctor Khan has said, for a couple of days no...
天啊
Oh man
可是我伤的是头啊
But I've got injured on my head,
而且汗医生是神经学家又不是性科学家
and Dr Khan is a neurologist, not a sexologist
她肯定是个百合...
I think she's a lesbian...
米拉!
Meera!
到这里来
Come here
你是不是又变漂亮了?
Have you become more beautiful than before?
为什么我觉得好多年没见你了?
Why does it feel like I am meeting you after so many years?
好多年没摸过你了
Touching you after so many years
别别别 别走
No, no, no, stay here,
就这么抱着
just stay here
汗医生允许这样 对不?
Dr.Khan's allowed this much, hasn't she?
汗医生...
Dr.Khan...
成天念叨汗医生的嘱咐
Dr.Khan has become Changez Khan,
把她电话号码给我
give me her telephone number,
作为一个女人 她一点也不善解人意
being a woman, she doesn't have the heart of a mother
我做不下去了
I can't do this any more
求你了 米拉...
Please, Meera...
再坚持几天...
just a few more days...
汗医生说萨马恢复得很好
Dr.Khan is saying that Samar is recovering very well,
他精神状态非常稳定
his mental condition is very stable
很快就会有能刺激他恢复记忆的事情发生了
and that very soon something may trigger his memory
我坚持不下去了 亚基拉
I can't go on, Akira,
医生 求求你...
doctor, please you...
我明白...
I understand...
真的
I do
理想的情况是两周之后再走这一步...
Ideally I wanted to take this step after two weeks...
不过也许现在就是个好时机...
but maybe this is the right time...
亚基拉 你去见萨马
Akira, you will meet Samar,
也许看到你他就什么都想起来了
maybe seeing you will trigger his memory immediately
虽然有点冒险
Yes, this is slightly risky
但目前这是我们最好的选择了
but at this point it is our best chance
我觉得是时候...
I think it's time...
让萨马・阿南德少校... 见见亚基拉了!
for Major Samar Anand... to meet Akira!
扎因 我不想去做这个访问
Zain, I don't want to do this interview,
你没必要逼我去
you're unnecessarily forcing me
萨马 这不是什么一般的访问
Samar, it's not just any interview,
这是探索频道啊 兄弟
these are the Discovery Channel guys,
他们要在伦敦寻访十个印度裔成功人士的故事
they're covering the success story of 10 lndians in London,
想想这对我们的餐厅是多好的宣传
imagine how good marketing it is for our restaurant
什么宣传!
What marketing!
干脆让我穿比基尼照些相片
Instead make me wear a bikini
然后把相片挂在餐厅外面好了
and put its photo outside the restaurant?
嘿 这主意也不错
Hey, that is also a good idea
你很兴奋嘛 帕坦人 巴帕帅
You're excited uh Pathan, PPK
嘿 别搞我的蓝牙耳机
Hey that's my Bluetooth
我们到了
Here, we've come
你怎么停这儿了?
Why have you stopped here?
探索频道的工作人员
The channel guys want to start off,
想从你刚来伦敦工作的地方开始寻访
from the first place you worked in London
快去 记者们在入口处等你
Now go quickly, their journalist is waiting at the entrance for you,
我要回餐厅去了
and I have to go to the restaurant, okay
拜拜
Bye
对于一个失忆的人
For one who can't remember anything,
她能采访些什么啊
what interview will she take of his
我是萨马・阿南德!
Samar Anand!
你好 我是亚基拉・拉埃
Hi, I'm Akira Rai,
探索频道的工作人员
Discovery Channel
额!
Uhh!
我们... 我们见过么?
Have... have we met before?
没! 没见过
No! I don't think so
对不起 我的记忆都休眠了
I'm sorry, my memory is on a long break
所以这些天很多人看起来都很熟悉
so these days every face looks familiar to me
没关系 萨马
It's okay, Samar,
我知道你的情况
I know about your condition
别担心 我不会麻烦你太多的
don't worry, I won't trouble you much
不 不 不怕麻烦
No, no, no, please trouble me,
也许这些有助于我恢复记忆
maybe that might help trigger some lost memory
好吧 准备好应付麻烦吧
Okay then, get ready for the trouble
我打扮得还行?
Uh make up okay?
-嗯 - 好
- Yeah - Yeah
我们开始?
Let's go?
在这里
Over here,
我以前扫过雪
I use to clean snow,
为杰克先生工作 四镑一小时
for 4 pounds per hour for Jack sir...
这里对我来说很特别
this is a very special place for me,
你叫亚基拉...对吧?
uh Akira... right?
并不是因为这是我的第一份工作
Not because this was my first job,
而是因为我就是在这里与米拉邂逅的...
but because this is where I saw Meera for the first time...
就在这里
right there
她穿梭于飞舞的雪花中
In the middle of white snow,
好像红衣仙女一样飘过雪地
Like a fairy dressed in red, glide across the snow
只用了一秒 我就爱上了她...
It took one second and I fell flat for her...
你还没见过我老婆吧?
you haven't seen my wife, hmm?
她是世界上最美的女人
She's the world's most beautiful woman,
我不知道她怎么会爱上我这样一个小丑
I have no idea how she fell for a clown like me
哦哇哦 我超爱这种车
Oh wow, this is my favourite bike,
我以前有过一辆 从一个朋友那买的二手货
I had this, I bought it second-hand from a friend
我能骑一下么 求你了?
May I ride it, please?
谢谢你
Thank You,
你也来啊?
you're also coming?
快上来
Come on
我以前是这间餐厅的经理
I was a manager in this restaurant, this whole restaurant
萨马!
Samar!
你好么?
How are you?
这是亚基拉 阿密特 我在宝莱坞找到工作了
This is Akira, Amit I found work in Bollywood
- 真的! - 是啊
- Really! - Ya
骗你的!
No!
谢谢
Thank you
如果不是弗兰克先生 我可能早回了旁遮普
If it wasn't for Frank sir, I would probably have gone back to Punjab
然后像我爸爸和祖辈一样参军
and join the army like my father and forefathers
我从没告诉我妈
I never told my mother
不过炸弹啊 枪啊 我真的好怕怕
but bombs and guns really scare me
弗兰克先生 他救了我
Frank Sir, he saved me,
谢谢你 弗兰克先生
thank you, Frank sir
我特喜欢萨马...
Samar was my favourite...
他魅力四射...
he could charm anyone...
三文鱼 我的最爱
Salmon, my favourite
请慢用
Enjoy
他就是享受让别人快乐的感觉
He just enjoyed making people happy
亚基拉 我在这里双班轮流
Okay Akira, I worked double shift here
这些是我的朋友们
These are my friends,
- 你好 伙计们 - 你好
- Hi guys - Hi Hello
这是贾巴尔 这是桑巴汗
This is Gabbar, this is Sambha,
这是我...
this is me...
这是巴桑提!
and this is Basanti!
你怎么回事儿?
What is wrong with you?
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
# 何处是我家? #
Where is my home?
# 他逢人必问 #
He asks every passer-by
# 亦曾欣喜 亦曾悲伤 #
Wanders with a smile...
# 他只身流浪 #
...and a tear
# 沿着街道漫无目的地流浪 #
Wanders aimless from street to street
# 处处为家 #
Belonging to all
我为米拉写了这首歌...
I wrote this song for Meera...
知道一切都是命中注定...
and see my fate...
就像今天这样的一个傍晚
it was an evening just like this,
我在唱歌...结果一睁开眼
I was singing... and when I opened my eyes
米拉就站在我眼前
Meera was standing in front of me
我声由心发 为她吟唱
For who my heart sung this song,
我的歌声令她怦然心动
it reached out and found her heart
这不是命中注定我爱你的爱情故事么?
Isn't it a made-for-each-other love story?
来吧 伙计们
Come on, guys
噢 兄弟 真高兴见到你
O, dude, cool good to see you
给你一张钞票
A note for you
# 这癫狂的流浪汉在寻找着什么? #
What does this crazy wanderer seek?
今天 我去见了萨马・阿南德
Today I met Samar Anand,
他就像个陌生人
a man who I had never met before,
我认识的萨马好像只是... 鬼魂
the Samar that I know is like... a ghost,
一个影子
a shadow,
再也不存在了
that's not alive
萨马只为爱你而活
Samar lives only to love you,
没有你他活不下去
without you there's no breath in his life
你知道吗!
You know!
我一整天都在想
I was thinking the whole day
如果我们同时出现在他的生命中
that if we were in his life together the same time,
会怎么样
what would happen,
就算在我的梦里 你也是遥遥领先
and even in my dreams, I was miles behind you
你不了解我
You don't know me,
我一直傲视群芳
I've been a topper all my life,
荣誉学生 每项运动都拿金牌...
an honour student, a gold medalist in every sport...
我每三个月就甩个男朋友
I dump my boyfriends every three months,
不会给他们甩掉我的机会
before they leave me,
因为我无法接受拒绝
because I can't handle rejection
所以在萨马恢复前 跟我大谈友情之前
So now before Samar recovers and lectures me on friendship and all,
我主动放弃这段感情...
I am getting out of this love...
虽然要花点时间 但是我会恢复的
it'll take time but then I'll be okay,
所以我来告诉你
So I've come to tell you that,
如果你是因为我而却步
if it's because of me that you're stopping yourself,
那你真的在浪费时间
then you're wasting time,
因为我从来就没有在萨马的爱情故事里存在过
because I've never existed in Samar's love story
他的爱情故事里一直都有米拉 也只有米拉
His love story's always had Meera and will only have Meera in it
我不是因为你才迟迟没有行动的 亚基拉
I wasn't stopping myself because of you, Akira
是因为萨马
It is because of Samar I'm stopping myself
每天我都想打破我的承诺跟他在一起
Everyday I want to break my promise and fall into his arms,
但是如果他出事了怎么办?
but what if something happens to him?
我是因为害怕 才一直克制自己
It is this if that scares me and why I stop myself
每天我都为他祈祷
Everyday I pray for his life
一天天坐等年华老去
and every day I die a little
现在说这个...上帝 祈祷 承诺啥的
Now this... God, prayers, promises and all,
我不懂...
I don't understand...
我很少祈祷...
I really don't pray much...
但是我走之前想告诉你...
but before going there's one tip I'm giving you...
你是为了让他活着所以离开他
You left him so that he stays alive,
可是如果你不跟他在一起
but now if you're not with him
他和死了没什么分别
he is as good as dead
也许你的上帝是想告诉你
maybe your God's trying to tell you,
嘿 米拉 够了
Hey Meera, enough is enough,
现在去为你自己而活吧
now go and live a little
再见
See you
喂 扎因
Ya, Zain
萨马 我们新餐厅的地址
Samar, our new restaurant's site
在大理石拱门地铁站前面 知道么?
is in front of Marble Arch Station, okay?
好的 你先去 我搭火车去
Okay, you get there, I'll catch the train and come
好的 快点
Okay come quick
女士们 先生们 紧急疏散 这边走
Ladies and gents we need to evacuate this station come this way,
大家这边走 快点
Everybody come on this way start moving up this way
大家这边走 通报中说车上有炸弹
Everybody up this way - Due to a reported bomb aboard the train,
各位乘客请马上出站
all passengers are requested to leave the station immediately,
请各位乘客从身边最近的出口撤离
by the nearest available exit
请遵照安保人员的指示
Please obey the instructions of the security personnel
通报中表示发现炸弹... 炸弹...
Due to a reported bomb... bomb... bomb
三分钟 再重复一遍
Three minutes copy
先生你不能呆在这里
Mister you can't be here,
车上有炸弹 请你马上离开
there's a bomb on board you need to evacuate now
十磅塞姆汀塑胶炸药
Ten pounds symtex,
可能还附有榴霰弹
possibly with shrapnel,
不是动敏式的
not motion sensitive,
远程遥控
remote detonator
查理...
Charlie...
他也许是个内行 让他过来
This guy might just know what he's talking about, let him through
我是唐古・维克托 191号控制点
Tango Victor, 191 control
排爆工作已完成
The bomb has now been defused,
重复 排爆工作已完成
I repeat the bomb has now been defused
真是太感谢你了
Thank you so much
先生 请问您尊姓大名?
What's your name Sir?
我是萨马・阿南德少校!
I'm Major Samar Anand!
印度军人!
Indian Army!
拆弹小组
Bomb Disposal Squad
萨马
Samar,
你在这儿干什么?
what are you doing?
为什么把我叫到这儿来?
Why have you called me here?
在我失去的众多记忆中
For all the moments that I have lost in the past,
今天我找回了这样一幕
today I have come to steal back one moment,
今天我将再一次 再娶你一次
today I'm going to,once again, marry you
你愿意嫁给我吗 米拉?
Will you marry me, Meera?
萨马 别这样 我们不能就这样结婚
Stop it, Samar,we can't just get married like this
为什么 为什么不能?
Why, why can't we?
你曾说我们就应该这样结婚
You'd said this is how we got married,
不需要婚礼 只有你我...
no celebrations, just you and me...
那么让我们重来一次... 为了我
So let's just do it again... for me
来吧 我先开始
Come on, I'll start
对不起 我不记得上次我说了什么
I'm sorry, what I said last time or how
也不记得是怎样说的
I don't remember,
但是这一次我只想说 我非常爱米拉
but all I will say this time is that I love Meera a lot
并且我保证我将会永远
and I promise that I will forever
不要说了 萨马
Stop it, Samar
这可不是玩笑!
This is not a joke!
哇 真是想不到
Wow, this is amazing,
你不仅把我们的婚姻当做玩笑 还欺骗了我
you've made our marriage a joke and lied about it
我就不能来个小小的恶作剧?
and I can't even play a small little prank?
记忆真是有意思...
Memory is such a funny thing...
我们用一生尝试着忘掉一些事情
we spend a whole lifetime trying to forget something
却忘不掉
but we can't
我们想记住的某些小小片段
and then if we try to remember some thing small
却怎么也记不住
we're unable to
你知道吗 米拉
You know, Meera,
在军队里的每一天我都会想
everyday in the army I used to think,
为什么上帝会让我活下来?
why is it that He keeps me alive?
今天我明白了...
Today I figured that out...
他对自己加诸于我身上的一切还不是很满意
He wasn't fully satisfied with what He had done to me
他先将我从你的生命中赶走
He first tears me away from your life,
他说走吧 去过那种没有她陪伴的生活
He says go... go live without her
所以每一天...
So I go and everyday...
我都徘徊在死亡的臂弯里 试图打败上帝
I live in the arms of death, hoping to defeat God
但是他就没输过
But out there also He kept winning,
他没让我死
He didn't let me die...
然后有一天 奇迹般的
and then one day, like magic,
他把你送回了我的生命中
He brings you back into my life,
接着送回了我失去的记忆
He brings back all my lost memories,
他让我再次飞翔起来
He makes me fly again
接着又出其不意地狠狠将我摔回地上
and then in a flash He slams me back onto the ground
他将我从梦中唤醒 就想告诉我
He wakes me up from my dreams and tells me,
你的生活不过如此了
your life is exactly how it is,
米拉 仍然是我的 你休想得到她
Meera is still Mine,she will never be yours,
因为直到今天
because even till today,
她向我许下的承诺
the promise she made to me,
比她向你许下的承诺要珍贵得多
is greater than the promise she made to you,
这么简单的事实你怎么就不明白呢
there's this simple little thing you don't seem to understand,
她爱我胜过于爱你
more than you, she's in love with me
如果你是为了另一个人而离开我
If you'd at least left me for another person,
我可怜他 也能原谅他
I would've felt pity and forgiven him
但是... 我该怎样可怜上帝?
But... how do I feel pity for God?
我要回去了
I'm going back,
十年来 我都习惯没有你的生活了
I spent 10 years without you
每天怀着对你的爱恋
By loving you every single day,
我再独自生活一百年都不是问题
I can live for another 100 years
要么... 要么上帝就杀了我
Either... either He kills me,
要么他就接受失败 将你送到我身边
or then accepts defeat and sends you to me
萨马...
Samar...
你的护照 飞机票...
Your passport, ticket...
入境登记表 我会帮你填的...
immigration form,I'll fill it for you...
入境登记处在那儿...
but the immigration is there...
我现在已经恢复记忆了 记得吗?
My memory is back now, remember?
我希望能将你从我的记忆里删除
I wish I could delete you from my memory
我曾是那么没心没肺的一个人
I was such a heartless carefree bitch
看现在你把我变成了什么样子
and now see what you've made me
亚基拉 问题是
Akira, the thing is,
上帝和我相处的不是很好
God and me don't get along too well,
但是我相信看到人之将死
but while dying
他甚至会听从我这个敌人的话
I believe He listens even to His enemies,
所以时机来临时
so when my time comes,
我会向他祈求来生
I'll ask Him for another life,
用下辈子去爱你!
to love you!
此生我生错年代了
This time around I was born in the wrong generation,
有一点过时了 不是吗?
I became a bit old fashioned, no?
但是我保证来生
But I promise next time
会成为像你一样的时髦恋人
I'll come as a modern lover like you,
我们会是英伦爱情故事里圆满的一对
and ours will be a full on English style love story
好极了 兵哥
Very good soldier,
你将我改造成了一个浪漫的人
you've made me into a complete romantic
你也越来越时髦了
and you're turning modern
如果你还会回来 就像现在这样回来
If you want to come, come back exactly like this,
从头到脚一模一样
from head to toe,
亚基拉怎么轮回都不会缺男朋友的
Akira will never have a shortage of boyfriends in any life
不要变成我这样...
Don't become like me...
太晚了 兵哥
Too late soldier
太晚了
Too late
待我给出解除警报的信号后再通告其他车辆
Inform the other vehicles only after I give the All Clear signal
好了 完毕
Alright. Over and out
安全了
We are safe
好的 长官
Okay, sir
- 克里斯南   - 到 长官
- Krishnan - Yes, sir
和以前一样...
Same again...
这些天都很平淡啊
Everything's become so common these days
我建议...你去支援大桥
I suggest...that you support the bridge
好的 长官
Okay, sir
今天是我的死期吗?
Am I going to die today?
萨马 这十年你并非独自承受苦痛
You didn't bear these 10 years all by yourself, Samar,
我同你一样 每天都是坐待年华老去...
I've been dying everyday along with you...
我用了十年才想明白这个简单的事
it's taken me 10 years to understand a simple thing,
并不是只有我离开你 上帝才容许你活下去
that He didn't keep you alive to be without me,
他让你活着 是让你和我在一起
He kept you alive to be with me
你怎么不早一点明白...
Couldn't you have understood this a little sooner...
早一点就好了
just a little
你一开始就知道的
You knew this from the beginning,
我得多花一点的时间才能想明白
that I take a little more time to understand things,
有人告诉我
and someone had told me
每段爱都有它的时机
that every love has it's time,
当时时机还不成熟
that time, was not ours,
但是现在 时机刚刚好
but this, is our time
长官 我们发现了另一枚炸弹
Sir we've located another LED
再等一会儿
Wait for some more time,
我把工作处理好就回来
I'll finish a bit of work and come back
听着!
And listen!
用不着祈祷
Don't pray for anything
爱我就足够了...
just love me...
炸弹也好 上帝也罢
because there's no bomb,
没啥能阻止我回到你身边
or God, that can keep me from coming back to you
我知道
I know
萨马・阿南德 "不死传奇"!
Samar Anand, The Man Who Cannot Die!
他拆过一百零七枚炸弹 毫发无伤
He has defused 107 bombs without a scratch on his body
我们说话的这会儿
He's right now as we speak
他正在拆除第一百零八枚炸弹
defusing his 108th
这不是一个有关勇气的故事
This is not a story of courage,
这不是一个有关... 奇迹的故事
its not a story of... miracles!
这只是一个简单的关于爱的故事
Its just a simple story of love,
男人付诸女人的永不磨灭的爱
undying love that a man had for a woman,
女人付诸男人的无畏无惧的爱
unflinching love that a woman had for a man,
还有上帝必将眷顾他们的无穷信仰
and unending faith that God had on their love
接触这个故事之前 我想着
I got into this story thinking
这是我入职搜索频道的敲门砖
that this was my big ticket to Discovery channel,
我以为我会倾向于讲述一个关于勇气
I'm going to discover a story of courage,
胆量 危险 或者奇迹的故事
bravery, danger, miracles
但是最后 我选择了爱
But I ended up discovering love
这种爱让你们两地分散
Love that breaks you,
却心意相牵
but still keeps you together,
这种爱让你们天涯海角
Love that creates distances,
却近在咫尺
but still brings you closer,
真实的
Love that is true,
永远的爱...
and forever...
我还发现
and I learnt that,
如果你有能力这样去爱一个人
if you have the power to love like that,
上帝定会成全你 让你情有所属
then God makes sure that your love finds its way
你要做的 就是坚持住
All you have to do is just hang in there
耐心地等待...
and wait...
等待你们的时机
wait for your time
就在我说话的这会儿
As we speak right now
萨马正在拆除他的第一百零八枚炸弹
Samar is defusing his 108th bomb,
最后一枚
his last one,
这当然不是因为他突然开始畏惧死亡
its his last not because he's suddenly scared of dying,
之所以是最后一枚
it's his last,
是因为现在是时候开始他的新生活了
because it's his time to live now,
他的等待终于功德圆满了...
his wait is finally over...
属于他的时机已经到来
his time has come...
成全自己的爱的时机!
his time to love!
你愿意嫁给我吗?
Will you marry me?
我愿意...
Yes...
这不是一个有关于勇气的故事!
This is not a story of courage!
不是一个有关于奇迹的故事!
It's not a story of miracles!
这只是一个简单的关于爱的故事!
It's just a simple story of love!